<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<pages xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
	<page id="index" section="index" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>The award-winning Sugar Learning Platform promotes collaborative learning through Sugar Activities that encourage critical thinking, the heart of a quality education. Designed from the ground up especially for children, Sugar offers an alternative to traditional “office-desktop” software. Unlike “apps”, Sugar empowers the learner by providing a collection of tools for problem-solving.</headline>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>Sugar is the core component of a worldwide effort to provide every child with equal opportunity for a quality education. Available in more than 25 languages, Sugar’s <link id="about_activities">Activities</link> are used every school day by nearly four-million children in more than forty countries.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>Originally developed for the One Laptop per Child XO netbook, Sugar runs on most computers. Sugar is free/libre and open-source software. <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/DocumentationTeam/Try_Sugar">Try it with a child today.</link></text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>more information for <link id="learners">learners</link> / <link id="parents">parents</link> / <link id="teachers">teachers</link> / <link id="contributors">contributors</link></text>
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<thumbnail url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_on_a_Stick">
					<image url="assets/soas_thumb_mirabelle.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>Sugar on a Stick</title>
				</thumbnail>
				<thumbnail id="gallery">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_01.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>The Sugar User Interface</title>
				</thumbnail>
				<!--
				<thumbnail id="learners">
					<image url="assets/narrative_thumb.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>The Sugar Experience</title>
				</thumbnail>
				-->
			</sidebar>
		</content>
	</page>

	<page id="about_overview" section="about_overview" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>What is Sugar?</headline>
				<text>The Sugar Learning Platform is a computer environment composed of Activities designed to help children from 5 to 12 years of age <keyphrase title="collaborative learning through rich-media expression">learn together through rich-media expression</keyphrase>. Sugar is the core component of a worldwide effort to provide every child with the opportunity for a quality education—it is currently used by nearly four-million children worldwide speaking more that 25 languages in more 40 countries. Sugar provides the means to help people lead fulfilling lives through access to a quality education that is currently missed by so many.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Runs on most PCs</headline>
				<text>Originally developed for the revolutionary <link url="http://www.laptop.org">One Laptop per Child</link> XO netbook, Sugar can run on almost any PC, including small netbooks, older and donated machines, and new energy efficient computers with limited processing power. Sugar is now packaged as part of most major GNU/Linux distributions and is compatible with recent Macs using virtualization. A liveCD which does not touch the existing hard disk installation is available; a liveUSB stick which can run on most PCs is under active development.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Why Sugar?</headline>
				<text>Sugar sets aside the traditional “office-desktop” metaphor and, through its Activities, engages even the youngest learners in the use of computation as a powerful “thing to think with.” They quickly become proficient in using the computer as a tool to engage in authentic problem-solving. Moreover, most Sugar Activities can be shared by learners between machines—children learn as a group, not as a collection of individual users. Sugar users develop skills that help them in all aspects of life.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>What is Sugar Labs?</headline>
				<text>Sugar Labs, a volunteer-driven, non-profit organization, is a member
				project of the <link url="http://conservancy.softwarefreedom.org">Software Freedom Conservancy</link>. The mission of Sugar Labs is to support the Sugar community of users and developers and <keyphrase title="establishing regional, autonomous &#8220;Sugar Labs&#8221;">establish regional, autonomous “Sugar Labs”</keyphrase> around the world to help children “learn how to learn” by tailoring Sugar to local languages and curricula.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<thumbnail id="media_16">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_16.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>Sugar on an Intel Classmate PC</title>
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
	</page>
	
	<page id="about_features" section="about_features" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>What makes Sugar different?</headline>
				<list>
					<item>Sugar <keyphrase title="facilitating sharing and collaboration">facilitates sharing and collaboration</keyphrase>: Children can write, share books, or make music together with a single mouse-click.</item>
					<item><keyphrase title="activities, not applications">Activities, not applications.</keyphrase>.</item>
					<item>Automatic backup of Activity work; no worrying about files or folders. Sugar’s Journal makes it almost impossible to lose any data.</item>
					<item>The <link id="media_05">Journal</link> records everything you do: It is a place to reflect upon and evaluate your work.</item>
					<item>Sugar runs on most computer hardware, including slower machines.</item>
					<item>Sugar is <keyphrase title="free software">free software</keyphrase>: It is written in the modern Python language and easily customized.</item>
					<item>Sugar is documented by its users: It is easy to use and teachers worldwide have created a wealth of pedagogical materials for it.</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<thumbnail id="media_05">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_05.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>Journal</title>
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>What are the benefits of using Sugar?</headline>
				<list>
					<item>Hundreds of tools for discovery through <keyphrase title="exploring, expressing, and sharing">exploring, expressing, and sharing</keyphrase>: browsing, writing, etc.</item>
					<item>Built-in collaboration system: peer-to-peer learning; always-on support; and single-click sharing.</item>
					<item>The Journal is a built-in portfolio assessment tool that serves as a forum for discussion between children, parents, and teachers.</item>
					<item>A discoverable learning platform: it uses simple means to reach to complex ends.</item>
					<item><keyphrase title="designing for local appropriation">Designed for local appropriation</keyphrase>: it has built-in tools for making changes and improvements and a growing global community of support. 25 languages are currently available.</item>
					<item>An <keyphrase title="emphasizing learning through doing">emphasis on learning through doing</keyphrase> and debugging: more engaged learners are able to tackle authentic problems.</item>
					<item>Available in a wide variety of forms: as part of GNU/Linux distributions; LiveCD, LiveUSB; and in a virtual machine.</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>What are the Sugar advantages?</headline>
				<list>
					<item>Superior pedagogical framework</item>
					<item>Unique collaboration and journaling (evaluation) features</item>
					<item>Large &amp; successful installed base with hundreds of activities</item>
					<item>Large and committed community base (both developers and teachers)</item>
					<item>24/7 community support; training and workshop materials available</item>
					<item>Rapidly expanding teacher-driven development</item>
					<item>Easily localizable and customizable</item>
					<item>Free open source software: no licensing fees</item>
					<item><keyphrase title="a global project">A global project</keyphrase>: no single point of dependency or failure</item>
					<item>Great potential for local job creation</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<thumbnail id="media_06">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_06.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>Uruguayan school children in a Chat Activity</title>
				</thumbnail>
				<thumbnail id="media_08">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_08.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>Write</title>
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
	</page>
	
	<page id="education" section="education" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<lead>The computer can help get new pedagogical approaches into the classroom. While getting computers into the hands of more children is undoubtedly of benefit, the question remains, “how does one maximize the learning that occurs?”</lead>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>A “learning-centric” approach</headline>
				<text>The question often is framed in terms of teacher-centric versus child-centric methods. With Sugar, we strive for a “learning-centric” approach, where teachers mentor students as they engage with powerful ideas, “<keyphrase title="teaching less and learning more">teaching less and learning more</keyphrase>.” While we want to give children access to knowledge—through media such as electronic books, the world-wide web, and multimedia—we also want them to acquire this knowledge by putting it to use and engaging in critical dialog. With Sugar, we help learners acquire knowledge by giving them tools that make them consumers, critics, and creators of knowledge; Sugar welcomes them as members of a learning community.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Learning is not a service—it’s a process of active appropriation.</headline>
				<text>One-to-one computing initiatives—where children have access to computing “anytime” and “anywhere”—is changing in the way software developers and computer-makers think about the education industry. Cross-community collaboration between technologists and teachers ensures that the ideals of <keyphrase title="freedom, sharing, open critique, and transparency">freedom, sharing, open critique, and transparency</keyphrase> will be part of the interface to learning that touches children in the world’s classrooms.</text>				
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>The free software culture</headline>
				<text>These ideas are embodied in <keyphrase title="the culture of free software is a powerful culture for learning">the culture of free software, which is a powerful culture for learning</keyphrase>. Educators are discovering the culture, technology, and values of the open source movement which engages both teachers and students: empowering them with both the freedom to act and the freedom to be critical. Criticism of ideas is a powerful force in learning and in fostering economic development; unleashing that is an important part of the mission. Teachers are learners too and Sugar provides a way for teachers and students to share. More than 50 percent of the patches (code contributions) in the most recent Sugar release came from our users; they have approproated the tools.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<paragraph>Memos on learning by Marvin Minsky
					<list bullet="false">
						<item><link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/What_makes_Mathematics_hard_to_learn%3F">What makes Mathematics hard to learn?</link></item>
						<item><link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Drawbacks_of_Age-Based_Segregation">Drawbacks of Age-Based Segregation</link></item>
						<item><link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Drawbacks_of_Age-Based_Segregation#The_50-minute_hour">What’s wrong with the 50-minute hour</link></item>
						<item><link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Memo_3#Role_Models.2C_Mentors.2C_and_Imprimers_and_Thinking">Role Models, Mentors, and Imprimers and Thinking</link></item>
						<item><link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Memo_3#Thinking_about_Thinking_about_Ways_to_Think">Thinking about Thinking about Ways to Think</link></item>
						<item><link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Memo_3#How_do_children_acquire_self-images.3F">How do children acquire self-images?</link></item>
						<item><link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Memo_3#Finding_Mentors_in_Network_Communities">Finding Mentors in Network Communities</link></item>
						<item><link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Questioning_General_Education">Questioning General Education</link></item>
						<item><link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Education_and_Psychology">Education and Psychology</link></item>
					</list>
				</paragraph>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
	</page>
	
	<page id="constructionism" section="education" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<lead>Sugar is based on Constructionism. Like any good theory, Constructionism is accurate on some points, and needs further research on other areas. But what is Constructionism? Is it true? Is it effective?</lead>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>Seymour Papert, the father of constructionism, slyly points out that simply giving a definition would not be a Constructionist way to teach you. Instead he suggests ways in which you can experience what works and what doesn’t in current Constructionist programs. We can be a little more explicit, but the need for experience remains central.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>In Piaget’s Constructivist theory of child development and learning, based on decades of research with children, understanding is something a child constructs internally out of experience and previous understanding (which in some cases will be misunderstanding), when the child’s brain is sufficiently developed to support the ideas involved.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>In Constructionist education on computers, “Aha!” moments—in which a child (or adult) who has been working on a problem without insight suddenly gets it—are deliberately fostered. Alan Kay gives examples of ten-year-olds, with appropriate guidance on where and how to look, and appropriate computer software to assist them, discovering essential concepts of calculus, such as the laws of constant acceleration with their geometric realization and their application to physics. The symbol manipulation and formal proofs have to be delayed to a more appropriate developmental stage, of course.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>Much more common still are opportunities to work together—using Sugar’s collaboration capabilities, built-in to its Activities—to construct something, and to explore all that is known and unknown and share the results. This is what Ivan Krstić told us captured the teachers in Latin America, who were no longer bound to the inadequate textbooks and teaching materials provided by the government. And after the teachers got it, the parents soon got it.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<thumbnail>
					<image url="assets/papert.png" width="223" height="337" border="false" />
					<title>Seymour Papert</title>
				</thumbnail>
				<paragraph><text>Related links</text>
					<list bullet="false">
						<item><link url="http://online.sfsu.edu/~foreman/itec800/finalprojects/annmariethurmond/publications.html">Seymour Papert and Constructionism</link></item>
						<item><link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/EducationTeam/Education_Bibliographies">Education Bibliographies</link></item>
					</list>
				</paragraph>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
	</page>
	
	<page id="about_activities" section="about_activities" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<text>Activities are what make Sugar unique. Many Activities can be shared between learners with a single click. Click on an icon below to learn more about each Activity. Download these Activities, and many more, in our <link url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/">Activities</link> section.</text>
			</paragraph>
		</content>
		<thumbnails>
			<thumbnail url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Journal">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_09.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Journal</title>
				<caption>Object and activity browser</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4028">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_17.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Read</title>
				<caption>Book &amp; PDF reader</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4201">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_28.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Write</title>
				<caption>Word processor</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Help">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_08.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Help</title>
				<caption>Documentation and Help for Sugar</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4069">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_04.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Chat</title>
				<caption>Collaborative discussion</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4024">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_02.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Browse</title>
				<caption>Web browser based on Mozilla Firefox</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Distance">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_06.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Distance</title>
				<caption>Measure the distance between two laptops</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4030">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_07.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Etoys</title>
				<caption>Learning, programming, &amp; authoring environment</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4076">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_03.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Calculate</title>
				<caption>A basic collaborative calculator</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4027">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_26.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Turtle Art</title>
				<caption>Pseudo-Logo graphical programming language</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4071">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_11.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Maze</title>
				<caption>A timed maze game</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4063">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_13.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Memorize</title>
				<caption>Compete against others to find matching pairs of images, sounds, or text</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4034">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_14.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Moon</title>
				<caption>View current lunar	phase and eclipse information</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4041">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_16.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Pippy</title>
				<caption>Introductory Python programming environment</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4082">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_15.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Paint</title>
				<caption>Simple paint activity</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Scratch">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_20.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Scratch</title>
				<caption>An easy-to-learn, multimedia programming language</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4192">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_19.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Ruler</title>
				<caption>Graphical cm/mm ruler and grids to take measurements of lengths and angles of objects</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4081">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_18.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Record</title>
				<caption>Photo, video and audio capture</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4086">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_05.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Implode</title>
				<caption>An entertaining game of logic</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/WikiBrowse">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_27.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>WikiBrowse English</title>
				<caption>Offline English Wikipedia snapshot</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4062">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_21.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>TamTam SynthLab</title>
				<caption>A sound and music synthesizer</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4059">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_22.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>TamTam Edit</title>
				<caption>A musical composition tool</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4061">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_23.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>TamTam Mini</title>
				<caption>A basic noisemaking and music creation suite</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4060">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_24.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>TamTam Jam</title>
				<caption>A virtual stage for collaborative musical perfomances</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4197">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_12.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Measure</title>
				<caption>Visualize sound waves and other data with this virtual oscilloscope</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4043">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_25.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Terminal</title>
				<caption>A command-line interface for young programmers</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4200">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_01.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Analyze</title>
				<caption>A tool for analyzing hardware and network information</caption>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org/en-US/sugar/addon/4056">
				<image url="assets/overview_activity_10.png" width="223" height="132" />
				<title>Log</title>
				<caption>A debugging tool</caption>
			</thumbnail>
		</thumbnails>
	</page>
	
	<page id="gallery" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<thumbnails>
			<thumbnail id="media_01">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_01.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Sugar User Interface</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_02">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_02.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Home</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_03">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_03.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Groups</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_04">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_04.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Neighborhood</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_05">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_05.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Journal</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_06">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_06.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Chat</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_07">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_07.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Browse</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_08">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_08.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Write</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_09">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_09.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Draw</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_10">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_10.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Memorize</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_11">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_11.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Etoys</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_12">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_12.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Turtle Art</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_13">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_13.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Pippy</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_14">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_14.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>TamTam Edit</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_15">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_15.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>TamTam SynthLab</title>
			</thumbnail>
			<thumbnail id="media_16">
				<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_16.png" width="223" height="167" />
				<title>Sugar on an Intel Classmate PC</title>
			</thumbnail>
		</thumbnails>
	</page>
	
	<page id="media_01" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<video url="assets/sugar_demo.mov" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Sugar User Interface</title>
				<caption>Quicktime, 11.5 MB / open as <link url="assets/sugar_demo.ogg">Theora (.ogg)</link></caption>
			</video>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_02" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_02.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Home</title>
				<caption>The Home view contains icons representing a child and his or her favorite activities, providing a space for starting or resuming activities. The Home view is a starting place for exploration.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_03" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_03.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Groups</title>
				<caption>The Groups view represents the people closest to the child. From the Groups view, children interact with friends and can join their shared activities.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_04" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_04.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Neighborhood</title>
				<caption>The Neighborhood view displays all the computers within a child’s connected community, and their shared activities. The Neighborhood view is a place for discovering new things and making new friends.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_05" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_05.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Journal</title>
				<caption>The Journal is an automated diary of everything a child does with his or her laptop. Children use the journal to organize work and revisit a past project. Teacher and parents use the journal to assess a child’s progress.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_06" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_06.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Uruguayan school children in a Chat Activity</title>
				<caption>Source: <link url="http://ceibalflorida.blogspot.com">The Ceibal Project</link></caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_07" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_07.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Browse</title>
				<caption>Browse is a simple Web application that allows children to access the Internet and share links among their friends.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_08" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_08.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Write</title>
				<caption>Write is a text editing activity featuring straightforward tools and a simple interface. It provides an easy way for children to write a story, craft a poem, or complete an essay, as well as more advanced features like image insertion, table creation, and layout operations. It also features collaborative real-time editing, so a group of children can work together to edit text easily and seamlessly.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_09" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_09.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Paint</title>
				<caption>The Paint activity provides a canvas for a child’s creative expression. Children can draw free-form images with a paintbrush and pencil, and use the dedicated toolbar to play and experiment with shapes. Text support, image import functionality, and an interactive placement system give children limitless ways to explore their creativity.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_10" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_10.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Memorize</title>
				<caption>Memorize is the classic matching-pairs memory game with a twist: each card can consist of any multimedia object, such as images, sounds and text. The memory game allows children to play with existing card sets, as well as create new ones themselves.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_11" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_11.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Etoys</title>
				<caption>Squeak Etoys was inspired by LOGO, PARC-Smalltalk, Hypercard, and starLOGO. It is a media-rich authoring environment with a simple, powerful scripted object model.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_12" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_12.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Turtle Art program created by a Uruguayan schoolchild</title>
				<caption>Turtle Art is an activity with a Logo-inspired graphical “turtle” that draws colorful art based on Scratch-like snap-together visual programming elements.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_13" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_13.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>Pippy</title>
				<caption>Pippy teaches Python programming by providing access to Python code samples and a fully interactive Python interpreter.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_14" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_14.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>TamTam Edit</title>
				<caption>TamTam Edit is a page driven event sequencer featuring a powerful music generator, a colorful and intuitive graphical interface to create, modify and organize notes on five virtual “tracks”, a palette of close to a hundred sounds and a music construction model that allows virtually limitless variations in all musical styles.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_15" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_15.png" width="709" height="532">
				<title>TamTam SynthLab</title>
				<caption>TamTam SynthLab is an advanced application for older children who are ready to venture into sophisticated sound design. SynthLab is a physics lab and sound synthesizer modeled on Max/MSP.</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	<page id="media_16" section="gallery" paginate="true" black="true">
		<media>
			<image url="assets/gallery_image_16.png" width="709" height="625">
				<title>Sugar on an Intel Classmate PC</title>
				<caption>Photo: Mike Lee</caption>
			</image>
		</media>
	</page>
	
	<page id="learners" section="learners" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_01.png" width="709" height="433" alt="In biology class Mr. Deepak asks the class to join his Browse activity, and shares a website about sharks with his students." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<paragraph topmargin="45">Sugar supports sharing and collaboration. Using Sugar, teachers easily share things with their class: books and bookmarks; materials and activities.</paragraph>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_02.png" width="709" height="511" alt="Kamala reads a webpage about sharks, and learns that shark populations are declining." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<paragraph topmargin="29">Using Sugar, children collaboratively <link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Browse">browse</link> the web. They share links directly within the collaborative browsing sessions.</paragraph>
				<thumbnail id="media_07">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_07.png" width="223" height="167" alt="" />
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_03.png" width="709" height="446" alt="Kamala opens a new Write activity, and starts writing her essay." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<paragraph topmargin="44">Sugar comes with many core activities, including <link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Write">Write</link>, a simple-to-use, collaborative word processor.</paragraph>
				<thumbnail id="media_08">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_08.png" width="223" height="167" />
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_04.png" width="709" height="413" alt="The schoolbell rings, and Kamala takes her essay and Sugar with her, to finish writing at home." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<paragraph topmargin="10">“<link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_on_a_Stick">Sugar on a Stick</link>” gives children access to <italic>their</italic> Sugar on any computer—they only need a USB key. At home or the library, they use the USB key on any computer to access their work.</paragraph>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_05.png" width="709" height="528" alt="Kamala walking home." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_06.png" width="709" height="449" alt="Kamala sees her friend Sanjey in the Neighborhood. She invites him to help her with her essay, and they begin writing together." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_07.png" width="709" height="396" alt="Kamala gets home and later signs back in to Sugar." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<paragraph topmargin="10">In the Sugar <link id="media_04">Neighborhood</link> view, children see their connected friends. Children are shown clustered around their current activities; they can join each other’s activities.</paragraph>
				<thumbnail id="media_04">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_04.png" width="223" height="167" />
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_08.png" width="709" height="531" alt="With the essay finished and recorded in her Journal, Kamala draws a picture of a shark, and adds it to her Memorize activity." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<paragraph topmargin="10">The Sugar <link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Draw#Paint:_A_collaborative_space_for_creation">Paint</link> activity provides a canvas for children to express themselves creatively by drawing.</paragraph>
				<thumbnail id="media_09">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_09.png" width="223" height="167" />
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_09.png" width="709" height="541" alt="Kamala working on her Memorize activity." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<paragraph topmargin="10">The Sugar <link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Memorize">Memorize</link> activity is a game about finding matching pairs of words, images, sounds—even videos. Memorize allows you to create new games yourself.</paragraph>
				<thumbnail id="media_10">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_10.png" width="223" height="167" />
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_10.png" width="709" height="492" alt="The next day, Mr. Deepak asks the students to share their homework. Kamala raises her hand." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_11.png" width="709" height="499" alt="Kamala opens her essay from the Journal and reads it to the class." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<paragraph topmargin="10">The Sugar <link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Journal">Journal</link> records everything a child does using Sugar. There is no need to remember to save files. The Journal allows children to focus entirely on their activities.</paragraph>
				<thumbnail id="media_05">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_05.png" width="223" height="167" />
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_12.png" width="709" height="473" alt="Kamala chatting with her friends in the Neighborhood." border="false" />
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<paragraph topmargin="10">Using Sugar, children can <link url="http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Chat">chat</link> and exchange objects—pictures, games, writing—with their connected friends.</paragraph>
				<thumbnail id="media_06">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_06.png" width="223" height="167" />
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<image url="assets/narrative_13.png" width="709" height="385" alt="Kamala chatting with her friends in the Neighborhood." border="false" />
				<caption>Illustrated by Dongyun Lee / <link url="http://www.dongyunlee.com">http://www.dongyunlee.com</link></caption>
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<paragraph topmargin="10">Sugar provides a simple yet powerful means of engaging young children in the world of learning that is opened up by computers and the Internet. Sugar promotes sharing, collaborative learning, and reflection. Children develop skills that help them in all aspects of life.</paragraph>
				<paragraph><link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/DocumentationTeam/Try_Sugar">Learn more</link> about how you can try Sugar.</paragraph>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
	</page>
	
	<page id="parents" section="parents" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>The Sugar Learning Platform</headline>
				<text>The award-winning Sugar Learning Platform is a <keyphrase title="revolutionary new approach to technology and learning">revolutionary new approach to technology and learning</keyphrase>. With Sugar’s Activities, your children will engage in exploring knowledge, expressing themselves through writing, drawing, video—even programming the computer. Working collaboratively, they can reflect upon their work and use Sugar to create a portfolio of their accomplishments.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>The Journal</headline>
				<text>With the Sugar Learning Platform, the age-old question “What did you do in school today?” takes on new meaning. Sugar maintains a diary (the <link id="media_05">Journal</link>) of what they make (nouns), how they make it (verbs), and with whom they are collaborating (proper nouns). You can sit down with your child and walk through the Journal to review progress and leave comments for the teacher.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Activities</headline>
				<text>The heart of Sugar is its <link id="about_activities">Activities</link>—not applications in the traditional sense, but ways of working and thinking together. Curious children can view the source code of Activities and even try their hand at programming. More traditional Activities such as a web browser, an ebook reader, a multimedia player, and a word processor, open a window to the Web (if connectivity is available), allow dozens or even hundreds of books to be stored and read, rich content to be played back, documents to be composed. Kids love games, and Sugar has several which aid learning and build dexterity. Sugar comes with a rich collection of music Activities, both for playing and composing music, and programming tools that are accessible to child as young as 4-years old, but interesting enough to keep a teenager engaged. A hallmark of Sugar is its simplicity—even pre-schoolers can use the Sugar basics—while putting no upper bound on the complexity of expression to which your child can reach.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Collaboration</headline>
				<text>Collaboration is fundamental in Sugar. Your child can collaborate with friends, family, and classmates—playing games, chatting, sharing bookmarks, and helping each other with homework.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Try Sugar</headline>
				<text>You can <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/DocumentationTeam/Try_Sugar">try Sugar</link> by downloading it to a CD or USB key and then using it to boot your desktop or laptop computer. (Sugar will not change anything on your computer—it uses the USB instead of your hard disk.) You can introduce Sugar to your child’s school using USB sticks as well. With Sugar, children grow into confident, joyful learners and realize their unlimited potentials.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<thumbnail id="media_12">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_12.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>Turtle Art program created by a Uruguayan schoolchild</title>
				</thumbnail>
				<thumbnail id="media_15">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_15.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>TamTam SynthLab</title>
				</thumbnail>
				<thumbnail id="media_11">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_11.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>Etoys</title>
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
	</page>
	
	<page id="teachers" section="teachers" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<lead>Imagine a classroom where instruction is complimented by learners engaged in self-discovery; where collaboration, expression, and reflection are integrated directly into the learning experience.</lead>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>Through the award-winning Sugar Learning Platform, students appropriate knowledge by engaging in activities that are authentic to them. With Sugar, your students at all skill levels can explore any curriculum goal more deeply. Your <keyphrase title="students will learn and they will learn to learn">students will learn and they will learn to learn</keyphrase>.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>Your students will enjoy learning more and they will improve in regard to traditional metrics such as reading comprehension. And you will enjoy mentoring them and learning along side them.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Features</headline>
				<text>Sugar is easy to learn: teachers and students discover how to use Sugar through exploration and  collaboration—together, you learn by doing.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>Sugar can accommodate a wide variety of students, with different levels of skill in terms of reading, language, and different levels of experience with computing. It is easy to approach, yet it doesn’t put an upper bound on a student’s personal expression.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>The Sugar interface always shows a students connected friends. Students chat with each other, support each other, critique each other, and share ideas. Activities such as peer editing are just one “mouse-click” away.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>Sugar uses a “<link id="media_05">Journal</link>” to record each student’s activities: both what they make and how they make it. The Journal serves as a place for reflection and assessment of progress—a portfolio that can be shared with teachers, parents, and the student as they progress through grade levels.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Pedagogy</headline>
				<text>Based upon 40+ years of educational research at Harvard and MIT, Sugar promotes “<keyphrase title="studio thinking">studio thinking</keyphrase>” through demonstrations, projects, and critiques, as well as “studio habits of mind”, by developing craft, engagement, persistence, expression, observation, reflection, and exploration. In the context of Sugar, studio thinking is applied not just to the arts, but to all disciplines.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>Reflective practice involves students applying their own experiences to practice while being mentored by domain experts. In the context of Sugar, the expert could be a teacher, a parent, a community member, or a fellow student.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>At the same time, Sugar is flexible; it works coherently with the wide variety of instructional frameworks, deepening the student’s learning experience. Sugar also provides access to internet learning resources.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>While Sugar is designed for elementary school classrooms, it will hold the interest of middle schoolers as well.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Getting started</headline>
				<text>Sugar is a great way to augment your classroom: it is simple; it is powerful; it is boundless; and it is free! Almost nearly 3 million children and tens of thousands of teachers around the world are using Sugar. <link id="about_features">Learn more</link> about Sugar and how you can be part of the Sugar revolution.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<sidebar>
				<thumbnail id="media_06">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_06.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>Uruguayan school children in a Chat Activity</title>
				</thumbnail>
				<thumbnail id="media_05">
					<image url="assets/gallery_thumb_05.png" width="223" height="167" />
					<title>Journal</title>
				</thumbnail>
			</sidebar>
		</content>
	</page>
	
	<page id="contributors" section="contributors" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>A learning and software-development community</headline>
				<text>There are many ways you can <link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_Labs/Getting_Involved">take an active hand</link> in making Sugar even better. <link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_Labs/Donate">Financial contributions</link> large and small are greatly appreciated and will be used to support grassroots learning innovations and face-to-face meetings between developers and educators. The community is organized into <link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_Labs">teams</link>. Please join a team in order to help us expand our educational, technical, and community goals.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Education goals</headline>
				<text>Sugar is useful only to the extent it is used by the learning community. Thus Sugar Labs is working with educators around the world to focus on these learning challenges:</text>
				<list>
					<item>To make Sugar and Sugar activities freely and readily available to learners everywhere</item>
					<item>To explore and share best practices</item>
					<item>To provide a forum for discussion and support for technology for learning</item>
					<item>To provide a mechanism for evaluation and dissemination of results</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Technical goals</headline>
				<text>Sugar supports the notions that learners should “share by default” and be able to “explore, express, debug, and critique.” We focus on solving the challenges that are relevant to these distinct aspects of the interface:</text>
				<list>
					<item>To make it “simple” to share Sugar activities</item>
					<item>To create versions of Sugar that run on multiple operating systems and on multiple hardware platforms</item>
					<item>To make it “simple” to write Sugar activities</item>
					<item>To make Sugar activities even more secure</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Community goals</headline>
				<text>Sugar Labs is here to <keyphrase title="supporting community innovation, entrepreneurship, and enterprise">support community innovation, entrepreneurship, and enterprise</keyphrase>. Sugar Labs would like to help community members start projects that help sustain and grow the Sugar technology and learning communities:</text>
				<list>
					<item>To provide local and regional technical and pedagogical support</item>
					<item>To create new learning activities and pedagogical practice</item>
					<item>To provide localization and internationalization of software, content, and documentation</item>
					<item>To provide integration and customization services</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
		</content>
	</page>
	
	<page id="contributors_teams" section="contributors" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Education team</headline>
				<text>The mission of the education team is to explain why Sugar is an ideal platform for learning, and to provide guidance and feedback to those who are working on how Sugar enhances learning. <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/EducationTeam">Learn more</link></text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Deployment team</headline>
				<text>The mission of the deployment team is to voice the needs of Sugar deployments to the Sugar community, to find ways to support those needs, to organize forums for the exchange of experiences between Sugar users and Sugar developers, and to build local Sugar Labs organizations worldwide. <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/DeploymentTeam">Learn more</link></text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Development team</headline>
				<text>The mission of the development team is to build and maintain the core Sugar environment. This includes specifying and implementing new features in conjunction with the Design team, fixing bugs as they are found by the Testing team and the Sugar community, and generally making Sugar awesome in all ways. <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/DevelopmentTeam">Learn more</link></text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Design team</headline>
				<text>The mission of the design team is to make Sugar beautiful, elegant, and highly functional. <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/DesignTeam">Learn more</link></text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>BugSquad</headline>
				<text>The mission of the BugSquad is to be responsive to incoming bug reports. The Squad needs to triage the bugs and work towards a solution with the reporters and the developers until the issue is solved. Therefore it has an important role in making the end product better and can be seen as the liaison between testers/users and developers. <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/BugSquad">Learn more</link></text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Documentation team</headline>
				<text>The mission of the documentation team is to provide the Sugar community with high quality documentation, including user manuals, programming references, and tutorials. <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/DocumentationTeam">Learn more</link></text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Marketing team</headline>
				<text>The mission of the marketing team is to articulate the benefits of Sugar (simplify), to promote these benefits as widely as possible (amplify), and to recruit volunteers to improve the Sugar experience. <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/MarketingTeam">Learn more</link></text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Oversight board</headline>
				<text>The mission of the oversight board is to ensure that the Sugar Labs community has clarity of purpose and the means to collaborate in achieving its goals. <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/Oversight_Board">Learn more</link></text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Wiki team</headline>
				<text>The mission of the wiki team is to maintain the Sugar Labs wiki, and to help the Sugar Labs teams and the greater educational community to collaborate effectively. <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/WikiTeam">Learn more</link></text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Infrastructure team</headline>
				<text>The mission of the infrastructure team is to keep the project humming along nicely, by maintaining and developing Sugar Labs’ collaboration and public-facing infrastructure. <link url="http://sugarlabs.org/go/InfrastructureTeam">Learn more</link></text>
			</paragraph>
		</content>
	</page>
	
	<page id="contributors_deployment" section="contributors" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<lead>The deployment team is in charge of answering the question: How can Sugar Labs facilitate the distribution and support of deployments of Sugar all around the world?</lead>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<text>The Sugar Labs mission provides an answer, namely to voice the needs of Sugar deployments to the Sugar community, to find ways to support those needs, to organize forums for the exchange of experiences between Sugar users and Sugar developers, and to build local Sugar Labs organizations worldwide.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>A local Sugar Lab would:</headline>
				<list>
					<item><keyphrase title="adapting the technology and pedagogy to an area’s culture and
resources">Adapt the technology and pedagogy to an area’s culture and resources</keyphrase> (e.g. developing activities and content specific to a region)</item>
					<item>Help translate Sugar to the local language(s)</item>
					<item>Support Sugar deployments in area schools</item>
					<item><keyphrase title="creating a local community">Create a local community</keyphrase> devoted to the Sugar Labs principles, making Sugar more open and sustainable</item>
					<item>Provide for communication between the local communities and the global Sugar Labs community</item>
					<item>Develop Local content and software that can be used not only for local purposes but also for the overall community</item>
					<item>Host, co-host or partner in the organization of conferences, workshops, talks and meetings related to the use or development of Sugar</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Organizational structure</headline>
				<text>A distributed project—we pluralized the name Sugar Labs deliberately—where there is a <keyphrase title="local sense of ownership and associated entrepreneurship">local sense of ownership and associated entrepreneurship</keyphrase> feels like the right course for us as an organization. Sugar Labs “central” is the community itself, which would be responsible for setting clear goals and maintaining any necessary infrastructure needed by the project as a whole, while the regional labs would use the own means to make Sugar relevant to their local communities.</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Conditions for success</headline>
				<text>What is the “business model” for a successful Sugar Lab? Some conditions for ensuring success might be:</text>
				<list>
					<item>A university connection as a local human resource</item>
					<item>A local pilot user group from which to learn</item>
					<item>A local passion or sub-goal that provides a rationale for the work</item>
					<item>Bi-directional communication with the global Sugar community and other Sugar Labs</item>
					<item>A <keyphrase title="sustainable and well-defined entrepreneurship model">sustainable and well-defined entrepreneurship model</keyphrase></item>
					<item>A program to reach out to local free-software community and local industry</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
		</content>
	</page>
	
	<page id="contributors_join" section="contributors" paginate="true">
		<content>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Join Sugar</headline>
				<text>The Sugar community is individuals, teams, and relationships. We all share one thing in common: we want to improve how computers are used in education. If you want to take an active hand in making Sugar even better, there are many ways you can help. What role do you want to fill?</text>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Content writer</headline>
				<text>Description of this role: Communicate through words.</text>
				<list>
					<item>Skills you possess or want to learn: Writing, editing, grammar (wordsmith), technical, explaining complex ideas well, teaching, DocBook, XML, Wiki markup, technical knowledge (specific and general)</item>
					<item>Teams associated with this role: <link url="#">Documentation Team</link>, <link url="#">Marketing Team</link>, <link url="#">Wiki Team</link></item>
					<item>Tasks typical in this role: Guides, how-tos, FAQs, knowledgebase (kbase), articles, marketing material, process/methodology docs, editing, release notes</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Designer</headline>
				<text>Description of this role: Communicate through images.</text>
				<list>
					<item>Skills you possess or want to learn: Inkscape, GIMP, OO.org, design, usability/interaction</item>
					<item>Teams associated with this role: <link url="#">Design Team</link></item>
					<item>Tasks typical in this role: Conference banners/flyers, Materials (t-shirts, CD covers, etc.), OS art (wallpapers, themes), publication design, Web design, icons, banners, mockups, stylesheets</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Developer</headline>
				<text>Description of this role: Communicate through code.</text>
				<list>
					<item>Skills you possess or want to learn: Python, C, RPM/Packaging, Bugfiling</item>
					<item>Teams associated with this role: <link url="#">Development Team</link>, <link url="#">Testing Team</link>, <link url="#">Infrastructure Team</link></item>
					<item>Tasks typical in this role: Test/break Sugar, design &amp; build Sugar, file bugs, build packages, code for OS, develop new features, develop new activities</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>People Person</headline>
				<text>Description of this role: Communicate through one-on-one contact.</text>
				<list>
					<item>Skills you possess or want to learn: People skills, event organization, customer service/support, enthusiasm</item>
					<item>Teams associated with this role: <link url="#">Marketing Team</link></item>
					<item>Tasks typical in this role: Conferences, local events, organizing events, Sugar Labs forum/IRC help/support tech, send out media/spread Sugar</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Translator</headline>
				<text>Description of this role: Communicate through interpretation.</text>
				<list>
					<item>Skills you possess or want to learn: English, Non-English native language, technical knowledge, diff, PO, translation, babel tool (kbabel, etc.)</item>
					<item>Teams associated with this role: <link url="#">Wiki Team</link></item>
					<item>Tasks typical in this role: Marketing, docs, websites, application translation, localization</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph>
				<headline>Web Developer or Administrator</headline>
				<text>Description of this role: Communicate through the World Wide Web.</text>
				<list>
					<item>Skills you possess or want to learn: Python, XML/XHTML, CSS, XSL/XSLT, TurboGears, Web app development, Linux system administration</item>
					<item>Teams associated with this role: <link url="#">Wiki Team</link></item>
					<item>Tasks typical in this role: Website pages, applications, stylesheets, toolchain, design, scripts, templates</item>
				</list>
			</paragraph>
		</content>
	</page>
	
	<page id="sitemap">
		<column>
			<title>Sugar (wiki)</title>
			<caption>
				<list>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Downloads">Get Sugar</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Getting Started">Get started</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar help">Get help</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_Labs/GettingInvolved">Get involved</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Submit Bugs/Problems">Submit bugs</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Request New Features">Request features</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Activities">Activities/software</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/DevelopmentTeam/Source Code">Get the source</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar Labs">Sugar Labs</link></item>
				</list>
			</caption>
		</column>
		<column>
			<title>Teams (wiki)</title>
			<caption>
				<list>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/BugSquad">BugSquad</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Deployment_Team">Deployment</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Design_Team">Design</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Development_Team">Development</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Documentation_Team">Documentation</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Education_Team">Education</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Infrastructure_Team">Infrastructure</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Marketing_Team">Marketing</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Oversight_Board">Oversight</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/WikiTeam">Wiki</link></item>
				</list>
			</caption>
		</column>
		<column>
			<title>Quick Links (wiki)</title>
			<caption>
				<list>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_Labs/Current_Events">News</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://planet.sugarlabs.org/">Planet</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Local Labs">Local Labs</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_Labs/Donate">Donate</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Community/FAQ">FAQ</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_Labs/Governance">Governance</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/recentchanges-url">Recent Changes</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Wiki_Team/Resources">Wiki help</link></item>
					<item><link url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_Labs/Getting_Involved ">Getting involved</link></item>
				</list>
			</caption>
		</column>
	</page>
	<xi:include href="press.xml"/>
</pages>
