	<pressrelease sortdate="20091208">
		<date>8 Dec 2009</date>
		<language id="français">
			<title>L’association à but non lucratif Sugar Labs annonce la version 2 de “Sugar on a Stick” qui améliore la lecture de livres électroniques et transforme n’importe quelle clé USB en une plate-forme éducative pour les enfants ; partenariat avec Nexcopy, Inc.</title>
			<paragraph>PARIS, le 8 décembre 2009 - Netbook World Summit - SugarLabs ® la communauté de volontaires développant la plate-forme éducative Sugar déjà diffusée à plus d’un million d’enfants dans le monde, annonce la sortie de Sugar on a Stick v2 “Blueberry” (Myrtille). Disponible en téléchargement sur <link url="http://www.sugarlabs.org">http://www.sugarlabs.org</link>, Sugar on a Stick peut s’installer sur toute clé USB de 1Go ou plus et permet, sans modifier l’installation, de faire fonctionner n’importe quel PC, netbook ou un Mac récent, dans l’environnement pour enfant Sugar. Sugar est également disponible pour la plupart des distributions GNU/Linux, peut fonctionner de manière virtualisée sur Windows et Apple OS X et intègre nativement des fonctionnalités de collaboration et de sauvegarde dans le Journal des activités. La dernière version de Sugar propose une navigation web simplifiée, améliore la gestion des réseaux sans fils, propose un portail de mise d’installation de nouvelles Activités pour enfant, facilite la configuration du clavier et intègre Gnash pour le support de contenus Adobe Flash. De nouvelles Activités comme Physiques et OOo4Kids complètement également les applications favorites comme Naviguer et Lire, qui sont adaptés à lecture de livres électroniques.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>“Sugar on a Stick est une merveilleuse manière d’expérimenter Sugar” commente Walter Bender, le président exécutif du Sugar Labs. “En cette période de fêtes de fin d’année, nous souhaitons rappeler aux parents et aux enseignants que les livres électroniques ne sont pas réservés à des coûteux lecteur dédiés, mais font partie du mouvement libre d’accès à la connaissance pour aider les enfants partout dans le monde à développer un accès critique à la connaissance et combler le fossé numérique partout où il existe.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar on a Stick intègre plusieurs activités de lecture de livres électroniques pour télécharger et visualiser des livres électroniques aux formats PDF, EPUB et DejaVu. De plus, l’Activité Read Etexts peut lire des livres électroniques à haute voix, permettant de convertir n’importe quel vieux PC ou un netbook à bas coût en un outil de lecture audio pour les personnes à vision réduite. Avec Sugar, les enfants peuvent même construire leurs propres livres électroniques. Des centaines de livres électroniques pour enfant sont disponibles sur des sites tels que le Projet Gutenberg, l’Internet Archive Children’s Library, epubBooks.com, Feedbooks.com et ManyBooks.net. D’autres sites proposent de la lecture en ligne, tel que l’International Children’s Digital Library.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Des projets pilotes d’utilisation de Sugar sont actuellement en cours dans des écoles aux Etats-Unis et en Europe. Les responsables d’écoles qui souhaitent déployer Sugar seront intéressés par la récente mise à jour du Serveur d’école XS qui permet un accès protégé à Internet et offre des services de connectivité pour les écoles: sauvegarde, distribution de contenu, accès filtrés à Internet et intégration Moodle. Pour accompagner les écoles intéressées par cette technologie, Sugar Labs a monté un partenariat avec Nexcopy, Inc basée à Rancho Santa Margarita en Californie, leader dans les solutions de duplications USB qui à ouvert le site <link url="http://recycleusb.com">http://recycleusb.com</link>. Nexcopy récupère les clés USB des particuliers ou des entreprises, les chargent avec Sugar on a Stick, et les renvoient au Sugar Labs pour distribution dans les écoles. Nexcopy a aussi offert une unité de réplication de 20 clés USB au Sugar Labs.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Greg Morris, Président de Nexcopy, commente “Nexcopy est fier d’être partenaire avec une organisation à but non lucratif comme le Sugar Labs. Nous somme convaincu que la plate forme éducative Sugar est, un pas dans la bonne direction pour permettre aux enfants d’être efficace avec les ordinateurs. Notre objectif est de donner au Sugar Labs le support et l’équipement nécessaire pour permettre le succès de cette opération philanthropique et permettre la production de masse d’un grand nombre de clés Sugar nécessaire pour un déploiement global. Je suis très honoré que Nexcopy fasse partie de ce processus.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>A propos du Sugar Labs: Sugar Labs est un organisation non lucrative de volontaires, membre du projet Software Freedom Conservancy. A l’origine intégré au projet One Laptop Per Child, Sugar Labs coordonne les volontaires dans le monde qui sont passionés par l’idée de fournir des opportunités d’éducation à travers la plate-forme éducative Sugar. Sugar Labs est soutenu par des donations et cherche des fonds pour accélérer son développement. Pour plus d’information, voir <link url="http://www.sugarlabs.org">http://www.sugarlabs.org</link></paragraph>
			<paragraph>A propos de Nexcopy Incorporated: Nexcopy Incorporated est spécialisé dans le développement et la production du plus performant outil de duplication de mémoire flash sur le marché. Pionner sur le marché des outils de duplications de mémoire flash, Nexcopy distribue l’Amérique Centrale et l’Amérique du Sud, l’Europe, l’Inde, l’Asie, la barrière Pacifique et le marché US via son siège en Californie.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar Labs est une marque déposée de la Software Freedom Conservancy. Les autres marques déposées sont la propriété respective de leur auteurs.</paragraph>
		</language>
		<language id="deutsch">
			<title>Gemeinnütziges Sugar Labs gibt zweite Version von Sugar-on-a-Stick frei mit verbesserter E-Book-Unterstützung, macht aus jedem USB-Stick eine Lernumgebung für Kinder; Partnerschaft mit Nexcopy, Inc.</title>
			<paragraph>PARIS, 8. Dezember 2009 — Netbook World Summit: — Sugar Labs(R), die als gemeinnützige Freiwilligenorganisation für über eine Million Kinder in aller Welt die „Sugar“-Lernumgebung bereitstellt, gibt die Fertigstellung von Sugar-on-a-Stick v2 „Blueberry“ bekannt.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Der freie Download unter <link url="http://www.sugarlabs.org">http://www.sugarlabs.org</link> kann auf einem gewöhnlichen USB-Stick mit mind. 1 GB installiert werden, um auf jedem PC, Netbook oder Mac direkt die kinderfreundliche Sugarumgebung zu starten, ohne das existierende System anzurühren. Sugar ist außerdem für GNU/Linuxdistributionen verfügbar, läuft virtuell unter Windows und Mac OS X, und ermöglicht vernetzte Zusammenarbeit im Unterricht sowie automatisches Speichern im Journal. Die neueste Sugarversion bringt unter anderem eine einfachere Navigation, verbesserte Unterstützung von Drahtlosnetzwerken, vereinfachte Aktualisierung der Aktivitäten für Kinder, einfachere Tastaturkonfiguration und ein besseres Gnash für die Anzeige von Adobe Flash-Inhalten. Neue Aktivitäten wie „Physik“ und „OOo4Kids“ gesellen sich zu aktualisierten Favoriten wie „Browsen“ oder „Lesen“, das E-Books wiedergeben kann.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>„Sugar-on-a-Stick ist eine großartige Möglichkeit, um Sugar kennenzulernen“, kommentiert Walter Bender, Geschäftsführer von Sugar Labs. „Wir wollen Eltern und Lehrer daran erinnern, dass es E-Books nicht nur auf teuren Lesegeräten für Gutbetuchte gibt. Als Teil der Bewegung für offenen Wissenszugang sind elektronische Bücher frei verfügbar, damit Kinder überall essentielle Lernfähigkeiten entwickeln können und die digitale Kluft, wo immer sie existiert, überbrückt wird“.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar-on-a-Stick enthält mehrere Aktivitäten zum Finden und Anzeigen von E-Books im PDF-, EPUB- und DejaVu-Format. Die „Read Etexts“-Aktivität kann E-Books laut vorlesen und macht damit jeden alten PC oder billige Netbooks zur Vorlesehilfe für behinderte Leser. Mit Sugar können Kinder sogar ihre eigenen E-Books erstellen. Tausende Bücher für Kinder stehen auf Webseiten wie „Projekt Gutenberg“, „Internet Archive Children's Library“, epubBooks.com, Feedbooks.com oder ManyBooks.net bereit. Andere Webseiten offerieren das Online-Lesen, so wie die „International Children's Digital Library“.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>An europäischen und amerikanischen Schulen gibt es Sugar-Pilotprojekte. Schulverwaltungen, die Sugar einsetzen möchten, werden sich für OLPCs kürzlich aktualisierte „XS“-Schulserver-Software interessieren, die ein „Sicherheitsnetz“ und Dienste auf Schulebene bereitstellt: Backup, Dokumentenverteilung, gefilterter Internetzugang und Moodleintegration. Um Schulen zu unterstützen, die diese Technik testen wollen, ist Sugar Labs eine Partnerschaft mit Nexcopy Inc. eingegangen. Gemeinsam mit der in Rancho Santa Margarita, Kalifornien beheimateten Firma, einem führenden Hersteller von USB-Kopierlösungen, wurde <link url="http://recycleusb.com">http://recycleusb.com</link> geschaffen. Nexcopy wird gebrauchte USB-Sticks sammeln, sie mit Sugar-on-a-Stick laden und an Sugar Labs zur Verteilung in Schulen weiterleiten. Außerdem hat Nexcopy eine 20-fach USB-Kopierstation an Sugar Labs gespendet.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Greg Morris, der Gründer von Nexcopy, erklärt: „Nexcopy ist stolz auf die Partnerschaft mit einer gemeinnützigen Organisation wie Sugar Labs. Wir glauben, dass die Sugar-Lernumgebung ganz klar ein Schritt in die richtige Richtung ist, um Kinder im Umgang mit Rechnern vertraut zu machen. Wir wollen für Sugar Labs die technische Ausrüstung bereitstellen, die benötigt wird, um dieses philanthropische Projekt zum Erfolg zu führen. Wir helfen bei der Produktion großer Mengen von Sugarsticks für einen globalen Einsatz. Ich bin geehrt, dass Nexcopy Teil dieses Prozesses ist“.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Über Sugar Labs: Sugar Labs ist eine gemeinnützige Freiwilligenorganisation und Mitglied der Software Freedom Conservancy (<link url="http://conservancy.softwarefreedom.org">conservancy.softwarefreedom.org</link>). Ursprünglich war Sugar Labs Teil des „One Laptop Per Child“-Projektes (<link url="http://www.laptop.org">www.laptop.org</link>). Nun koordiniert Sugar Labs Freiwillige aus aller Welt, die sich leidenschaftlich dafür einsetzen, Kindern durch die Lernplattform „Sugar“ pädagogische Möglichkeiten zu eröffnen. Sugar Labs wird durch Spenden gefördert und sucht nach Sponsoren, um die Entwicklung zu beschleunigen. Weitere Informationen finden Sie auf www.sugarlabs.org.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Über Nexcopy Incorporated: Nexcopy Incorporated spezialisiert sich auf die Entwicklung und Herstellung der hochwertigsten und vielseitigsten Flashspeicher-Duplikatoren am Markt. Als Wegbereiter des Marktes für die Vervielfältigung von Halbleiterspeichern bedient Nexcopy Mittel- und Südamerika, Europa, Indien, Asien, den Pazifikraum und die USA aus ihrem Hauptquartier in Kalifornien.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar Labs ist eingetragenes Warenzeichen der Software Freedom Conservancy. Andere Namen sind Warenzeichen ihrer jeweiligen Inhaber.</paragraph>
		</language>
	</pressrelease>
	<pressrelease sortdate="20090918">
		<date>18 Sep 2009</date>
		<language id="english">
			<title>Sugar Labs and Free Software Foundation Celebrate Software Freedom Day, Announce Joint Efforts to Promote the Sugar Learning Platform for Children Worldwide</title>
			<paragraph>CAMBRIDGE, MA, September 18, 2009 - Sugar Labs, nonprofit provider of the Sugar Learning Platform for children, and the Free Software Foundation (FSF), which promotes computer users’ right to use, study, copy, modify, and redistribute computer programs, have announced joint efforts to collaborate and promote Sugar on the occasion of Software Freedom Day, September 19th. The FSF will host an event in Boston featuring Sugar Labs Executive Director Walter Bender, FSF president Richard Stallman, and other speakers. Peter Brown, FSF’s executive director, said, “The Sugar Learning Platform is fast becoming an essential route to computer user freedom for children around the world. The international free software movement is getting behind Sugar, and we want to use Software Freedom Day as an opportunity to help draw community attention, developer resources, and external funders to the important work going on at Sugar Labs.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>The FSF has upgraded its hosting services support of Sugar Labs to keep pace with its growth. As part of the ongoing relationship, Bernardo Innocenti, a member of the Sugar Labs Oversight Board, is working at the FSF offices. Mr. Innocenti stated: “The FSF and Sugar Labs are pursuing distinct, but interdependent goals; Free (as in Freedom) Software is a fundamental part of globally accessible education, and good education enables critical thought, a pre-requisite for appreciating the value of Freedom.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar is a global project. Translated into 25 languages, it is used in classrooms in 40 countries by over 1 million children as part of the One Laptop per Child (OLPC) nonprofit program. Sugar’s simple interface, built-in collaboration, and automatic backup through each student’s Journal have been designed to interest young learners. The recently released Sugar on a Stick (SoaS) project brings Sugar to even more children, allowing young learners to keep a working copy of Sugar on a simple USB stick, ready to start up any PC or netbook with the child’s environment and data. Pilot projects in schools with Sugar on a Stick are underway in Boston, Berlin, and elsewhere. SoaS is free software available under the General Public License (GPL) and is available for download without charge <link url="http://www.sugarlabs.org">sugarlabs.org</link>.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>According to Walter Bender, “Sugar is running on over 99% of all of the OLPC-XO laptops around the world because governments prefer its quality, openness, built-in collaboration, and easy localization to indigenous languages. Teachers and students are exercising their freedom by modifying and improving Sugar and its Activities. With Sugar on a Stick, access to Sugar is even more widespread.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>For example, Uruguay has distributed a Sugar-equipped OLPC laptop to every student in the country. Alexandre Oliva of FSF’s sister organisation Free Software Foundation Latin America (<link url="http://www.fsfla.org">http://www.fsfla.org</link>) said, “I was amazed when I first saw Sugar in action in Peru two years ago; shortly thereafter, my daughter tasted Sugar and loved it. She’s going to elementary school next year, and I’m very happy she can now easily carry Sugar with her, and share it with her friends. Myself, I’m going to spread its freedom into as many schools as I can.” Karsten Gerloff, President of Free Software Foundation Europe (<link url="http://fsfe.org">http://fsfe.org</link>), added: “Education and Free Software are both all about sharing knowledge. Through projects like Sugar, young people around the world can discover the creativity that freedom makes possible. Together with the political backing thatFSFE’s Edu-Team and others are building, Sugar puts Free Software inits rightful place in education.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar Labs relies on the efforts of software developers who donate their skills to the project. Mr. Bender continued, “We are looking for developers with experience in GNU/Linux, Python and/or Gtk+ for contributing to the Sugar shell and educational Activities for children. We also need testers, experienced packagers, and educators willing to contribute their ideas for Sugar in the classroom.”</paragraph>
		</language>
	</pressrelease>
	<pressrelease sortdate="20090624">
		<date>24 Jun 2009</date>
		<language id="english">
			<title>Sugar Labs Announces Immediate Availability of Sugar on a Stick; Learning Platform Runs on Any PC or Netbook In The Classroom</title>
			<paragraph>LinuxTag, Berlin, June 24, 2009: Sugar Labs™, nonprofit provider of the Sugar Learning Platform to over one-million children worldwide, announces the immediate availability of Sugar on a Stick v1 Strawberry. Available free for download at <link url="http://www.sugarlabs.org">www.sugarlabs.org</link>, Sugar on a Stick can be loaded onto an ordinary 1GB USB flash drive and used to reboot any PC or netbook directly into the award-winning Sugar environment. It runs on recent Macs with a helper CD and in Windows using virtualization. Sugar on a Stick is designed to work with a School Server that can provide content distribution, homework collection, backup services, Moodle integration, and filtered access to the Internet. Today’s Strawberry release is meant for classroom testing; <link url="mailto:feedback@sugarlabs.org">feedback</link> will be incorporated into the next version, available towards the end of 2009.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>“One year after its founding, Sugar Labs is delivering on its education promise for its second million learners,” commented Walter Bender, founder and executive director. “Sugar is preferred because it is a superior learning experience for young children: engaging while being affordable. Sugar on a Stick is a great way to try Sugar without touching your computer’s hard disk. It is also well suited to slower, older PCs and low-powered netbooks. There is a version for the OLPC XO-1 and it will ship with the newer XO-1.5 laptops in the fall.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar on a Stick provides a coherent and consistent computing experience. It reduces costs by providing flexibility in hardware choices, allowing schools to keep their existing investment in hardware. Learners can benefit from the increased household ownership of computers; by bringing Sugar on a Stick home, every student has a consistent, comparable computing environment that parents can share in as well. It also provides off-line access to applications and content as not every learner has Internet access at home.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>As part of an ongoing effort to make Sugar on a Stick classroom-ready, Sugar Labs has been awarded a $20,000 grant from the Gould Charitable Foundation to implement Sugar at the Gardner Pilot Academy, a public elementary school located in one of the most culturally and linguistically diverse sections of Boston, Massachusetts.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Learning Activities are at the heart of Sugar. Sugar on a Stick includes 40 Activities to interest young learners such as Read, Write, Paint, and Etoys. Hundreds more Activities are available free for download at the <link url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org">Sugar Activity Library</link>. Most “Sugarized” Activities have student collaboration built-in; students and teachers work, play, and learn on the same Activities together. The Sugar Learning Platform is open, so by leveraging the work of other open source projects, existing software for children can be integrated; for example, the acclaimed GCompris suite of 100 Activities developed over the past five years by Bruno Coudoin was recently added to Sugar, including Activities such as Chess, Geography, and Sudoku. Teachers and parents interested in Sugar’s Activities and its modern interface for children can watch short videos on the recently opened <link url="http://www.dailymotion.com/sugarlabs">Sugar Labs Dailymotion channel</link>.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Visitors to LinuxTag are welcome to speak with Sugar Labs contributors at booth 7.2a 110a.</paragraph>
		</language>
		<language id="français">
			<title>Sugar Labs annonce la disponibilité immédiate de « Sugar on a Stick », une plate-forme d’apprentissage qui fonctionne sur n’importe quel PC ou netbook dans la salle de classe</title>
			<paragraph>LinuxTag, Berlin, 24 Juin 2009: Sugar Labs™, fournisseur à but non-lucratif de la plate-forme pédagogique Sugar à plus d’un million d’enfants dans le monde, annonce la disponibilité immédiate de « Sugar on a Stick v1 Strawberry » (« Bâtonnet de Sucre v1 Fraise »). Logiciel libre disponible en téléchargement gratuit sur <link url="www.sugarlabs.org">www.sugarlabs.org</link>, Sugar on a Stick peut être chargé sur une clef USB 1Gb ordinaire et utilisée pour rebooter n’importe quel PC ou netbook dans l’environnement Sugar.  Celui-ci tourne sur les Macs récents avec un CD de support et dans Windows en utilisant la virtulisation.  Sugar on a Stick est conçu pour marcher avec un serveur d’école qui peut dispenser des contenus, des collections de devoirs à la maison, des services de sauvegarde, l’intégration de Moodle, et un filtrage de l’accès à internet.  La version « Fraise » d’aujourd’hui est destinée à être testée dans la salle de classe; les <link url="mailto:feedback@sugarlabs.org">retours d’expérience</link> seront intégrés dans la prochaine version, disponible vers la fin 2009.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>« Un an après sa fondation, Sugar Labs tient ses promesses pédagogiques pour son second million d’apprenants », commente Walter Bender, fondateur et directeur exécutif.  « Sugar est choisi parce qu’il permet une expérience d’apprentissage supérieure pour les jeunes enfants qui l’explorent, tout en étant abordable.  Sugar on a Stick est une formidable manière de tester Sugar sans toucher au disque dur de votre ordinateur.  C’est aussi bien adapté aux ordinateurs plus lents, aux vieux PCs et aux netbooks peu puissants.  Il y a une version pour le XO-1 d’OLPC et cela sera expédié avec les nouveaux XO-1.5 à partir de l’automne."</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar on a Stick fournit une expérience informatique cohérente et conforme. Il réduite les coûts en rendant souple les choix des matériels, permettant aux écoles de conserver leur investissement existant en matériel. Les apprenants peuvent bénéficier du taux grandissant des ordinateurs familiales ; en rentrant à la maison avec Sugar on a Stick, chaque étudiant possède son environnement habituel que les parents peuvent partager aussi. Il fournit aussi un accès différé aux applications et contenus, utile pour des apprenants dépourvus d’un accès Internet à la maison.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>L’effort pour rendre Sugar on a Stick prêt pour la salle de classe continue ; Sugar Labs a décerné une subvention de $20.000 de la Gould Charitable Foundation pour implementer Sugar au Gardner Pilot Academy, une école primaire publique située dans un quartier populaire et multicultuel de Boston dans l’état de Massachusetts.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Les Activités pour apprendre sont au cœur de Sugar. Sugar on a Stick est fourni avec 40 Activités intéressantes pour des jeunes apprenants tel que Lire, Ecrire, Dessiner, et EToys. Des centaines d’autres Activités sont disponibles gratuitement sur le <link url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org">Bibliothèque d’Activités Sugar</link>. la plupart d’activités « sucrées » offrent la collaboration en natif ; les étudiants et enseignants travaillent, jouent, et apprennent ensembles sur les mêmes Activités. La plate-forme d’apprentissage Sugar est ouvert et bénéficie des travaux d’autres projets ; des logiciels existants peuvent être intégrés. Par exemple, plus de 100 activités tel que Echecs, Géographie, et Sudoku de la suite acclamée GCompris développé depuis cinq ans par Bruno Coudoin ont été ajoutés récemment à Sugar. Des enseignants et parents qui s’intéressent aux activités de Sugar et son interface moderne pour enfants peuvent visionner des vidéos courts sur le nouveau canal <link url="http://www.dailymotion.com/sugarlabs">Dailymotion de Sugar Labs</link>.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Les visiteurs à LinuxTag sont invités à dialoguer avec des contributeurs de Sugar Labs au stand 7.2a 110a.</paragraph>
		</language>
		<language id="deutsch">
			<title>Sugar Labs gibt die Veröffentlichung von Sugar on a Stick bekannt; die Lernplattform läuft auf jedem PC oder Netbook im Klassenzimmer.</title>
			<paragraph>LinuxTag, Berlin, 24. Juni 2009: Sugar Labs™, gemeinnütziger Anbieter der Sugar-Lernplattform, die weltweit von über einer Million Kindern benutzt wird, gibt die Veröffentlichung von Sugar on a Stick v1 Strawberry bekannt. Frei zum Download auf <link url="www.sugarlabs.org">www.sugarlabs.org</link> verfügbar, lässt sich Sugar on a Stick auf einen gewöhnlichen 1GB-USB-Stick laden, von dem aus ein PC oder Netbook direkt in die preisgekrönte Sugar-Umgebung gebootet werden kann. Es läuft auf neuen Macs mit einer Hilfs-CD und unter Windows mittels Virtualisierung. Sugar on a Stick ist für den Betrieb mit einem Schulserver ausgelegt, der die Verteilung von Materialien, das Einsammeln von Hausaufgaben, Datensicherung, Moodle-Anbindung und gefilterten Zugriff auf das Internet bieten kann. Die gegenwärtige Strawberry-Version ist zum Testen im Klassenzimmer gedacht. <link url="mailto:feedback@sugarlabs.org">Rückmeldungen</link> werden in die nächste Version einfließen, die ende 2009 verfügbar sein wird.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>"Ein Jahr nach seiner Gründung arbeitet Sugar Labs an der Auslieferung seiner Bildungszusage an die zweite Million Lernender", so Walter Bender, Gründer und Geschäftsführer. "Sugar wird bevorzugt, weil es kleinen Kindern eine überragende Lernerfahrung bietet: faszinierend und doch erschwinglich. Sugar on a Stick stellt eine wunderbare Möglichkeit dar, Sugar auszuprobieren, ohne die Festplatte des Rechners zu verändern. Es eignet sich auch gut für langsamere, ältere Rechner oder schwachbrüstige Netbooks. Es gibt eine Version für den OLPC XO-1 und es wird auf den neueren XO-1.5-Laptops diesen Herbst zu finden sein."</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar on a Stick bietet eine schlüssige und einheitliche Computererfahrung. Es mindert die Kosten durch hohe Flexibilität bei der Hardware-Auswahl, was es Schulen ermöglicht, bereits vorhandene Hardware weiterhin zu nutzen. Die Lernenden können von der zunehmenden Verbreitung von Rechnern in den Haushalten profitieren: Dadurch, dass sich Sugar on a Stick mit nach Hause nehmen lässt, steht jedem Schüler eine einheitliche, vergleichbare Computerumgebung zur Verfügung, die seine Eltern ebenso nutzen können. Auch ermöglicht es Offline-Zugang zu Anwendungen und Materialien, nachdem nicht jeder Lernende zu Hause über einen Internet-Zugang verfügt.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Als Teil der andauernden Bemühungen, Sugar on a Stick für den Einsatz im Klassenzimmer bereit zu machen, wurde Sugar Labs ein 20.000$-Zuschuss der Gould Charitable Foundation zuerkannt, um Sugar an der Gardner Pilot Academy zu implementieren, einer öffentlichen Grundschule in einem der kulturell und sprachlich vielfältigsten Viertel Bostons in Massachusetts, USA.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Lernaktivitäten bilden das Herzstück von Sugar. Sugar on a Stick umfasst 40 Aktivitäten, um das Interesse junger Lernender zu wecken, beispielsweise Lesen, Schreiben, Malen oder Etoys. Hunderte weiterer Aktivitäten stehen in der <link url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org">Sugar-Aktivitätenbibliothek</link> zum freien Download bereit. Die meisten "ver-Sugar-ten" Aktivitäten ermöglichen die Zusammenarbeit von Schülern: Schüler und Lehrer arbeiten, spielen und lernen gemeinsam in denselben Aktivitäten. Die Sugar-Lernplattform ist offen, sodass durch Einsatz anderer Open-Source-Produkte vorhandene Software für Kinder integriert werden kann. So wurde etwa die gefeierte GCompris-Suite aus 100 Aktivitäten, die die letzten fünf Jahre über von Bruno Coudoin entwickelt wurde, erst kürzlich zu Sugar hinzugefügt, darunter Aktivitäten wie Schach, Geographie oder Sudoku. Lehrer und Eltern, die sich für Sugars Aktivitäten und sein modernes Interface für Kinder interessieren, finden im unlängst eröffneten <link url="http://www.dailymotion.com/sugarlabs">Sugar Labs Dailymotion-Kanal</link> kurze Videos.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Besucher des LinuxTages sind herzlich eingeladen, mit Beitragenden zu Sugar Labs am Stand 7.2a 110a zu sprechen.</paragraph>
		</language>
		<language id="español">
			<title>Sugar Labs anuncia la disponibilidad inmediata de Sugar On A Stick (Sugar en un pendrive). El plataforma de aprendizaje funciona en casi cualquier PC o portátil que hay en el aula.</title>
			<paragraph>LinuxTag, Berlín, 24 de junio de 2009: Sugar Labs™, proveedor sin fines de lucro de la plataforma de aprendizaje de Sugar a más de un millón de niños en todo el mundo, anuncia la disponibilidad inmediata de Sugar on a Stick (SoaS) v1 Strawberry  (Fresa). Disponible para su descarga gratuita en <link url="www.sugarlabs.org">www.sugarlabs.org</link>, SoaS se pueden cargar en una pendrive USB de 1 GB y se utiliza para reiniciar casi cualquier PC, o usar directamente en el portátil y entrar Sugar, el ambiente premiado de aprendizaje. Funciona en los últimos equipos Mac con un la ayuda de un CD y en Windows usando la virtualización. Sugar on a Stick está diseñado para trabajar con un servidor de colegio que puede proporcionar la distribución de contenidos, el recojo de tareas, los servicios de copia de seguridad, la integración de Moodle, y la filtración el acceso al Internet. El Strawberry  de hoy está listo para probarse en las escuelas. <link url="mailto:feedback@sugarlabs.org">Comentarios</link> se incorporará en la próxima versión, disponible a finales de 2009.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>"Un año después de su fundación, Sugar Labs es el cumplimiento de su promesa de educación para su segundo millón de estudiantes", comentó Walter Bender, fundador y director ejecutivo. "Sugar es preferido porque es un excelente experiencia de aprendizaje para los niños pequeños: divertido y  económica. "Sugar on a Stick es una gran manera de probar Sugar sin tocar el disco duro de la computadora. También, es muy adecuado para las computadoras más lentas, más antiguas y para las portátiles pequeñas de baja potencia. Existe una versión para la OLPC XO-1 y se suministran con los nuevas computadoras portátiles XO-1.5 en el otoño."</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar on a Stick ofrece una coherente y consistente experiencia. Reduce costos, proporcionando flexibilidad en opciones de tipos de computadoras, permitiendo que las escuelas  mantengan sus inversiones exsitentes en sus aparatos. Para los que tienen computadora en casa, pueden  traer el Sugar on a Stick a casa. Cada estudiante tiene un ambiente de computación coherente y comparable que los padres pueden compartir también. También proporciona acceso fuera de línea a aplicaciones y contenido para los alumnos que no tienen acceso al Internet en casa.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Como parte de un esfuerzo continuo para hacerlo Sugar on a Stick listo para las aulas, Sugar Labs ha recibido una subvención de 20.000 dólares de la Fundación de Beneficencia Gould para aplicar un proyecto piloto de Sugar en la Academia Gardner, una escuela primaria ubicada en una de las más cultural y lingüísticamente diversas secciones de Boston, Massachusetts.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Actividades dirigidas al aprendizaje están in el corizon de Sugar. Sugar on a Stick incluye 40 Actividades de interés para los jóvenes estudiantes tales como Leer, Escribir, Pintura, y Etoys. Cientos de Actividades están disponibles para su descarga gratuita en la <link url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org">biblioteca de la Actividades de Sugar</link>. La mayoría de los "Sugarized" Actividades se han incorporado la colaboración de estudiantes. Los alumnos y profesores juntos trabajan, jugan y aprenden en las mismas actividades. La plataforma de aprendizaje de Sugar está abierta. Por lo tanto, Sugar utiliza el trabajo de otros proyectos de código abierto. El software existente para los niños se puede integrar a Sugar. Por ejemplo, el reconocido GCompris, junto con 100 actividades desarrolladas en los últimos cinco años por Bruno Coudoin, fueron añadidos recientemente al Sugar; incluye actividades como el Ajedrez, Geografía, y Sudoku. Los maestros y los padres de familia interesados en los Actividades de Sugar y su interfaz moderna pueden ver videos cortos en el recientemente inaugurado canal de <link url="http://www.dailymotion.com/sugarlabs">Sugar Labs Dailymotion</link>.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Los visitantes a LinuxTag son bienvenidos a hablar con azúcar Labs contribuyentes en el mostrador 7.2a 110a</paragraph>
		</language>
		<language id="italiano">
			<title>Sugar Labs annuncia l’immediata disponibilità di Sugar on a Stick; La Piattaforma di Apprendimento in grado di funzionare su qualsiasi PC o Netbook disponibile in classe</title>
			<paragraph>Berlino, 24 Giugno, 2009: Sugar Labs, la realtà no-profit che ha sviluppato la Piattaforma di Apprendimento Sugar (Sugar Learning Platform) utilizzata da più di un milione di bambini nel mondo intero, annuncia l’immediata disponibilità di "Sugar on a Stick" v1 Strawberry. Disponibile in forma libera e gratuita dal sito <link url="www.sugarlabs.org">www.sugarlabs.org</link>, Sugar on a Stick può essere caricato su una normale chiavetta USB da almeno 1Gb e utilizzandola per avviare direttamente il sistema Sugar in qualunque PC o netbook. Può essere utilizzato anche sui più recenti sistemi Mac con l’ausilio di un CD di avvio, e all’interno di sistemi  Windows attraverso la virtualizzazione. “Sugar on a Stick” è stato progettato per l’utilizzo insieme ad uno Server di Classe (School Server) che fornisce distribuzione di contenuti, raccolta di elaborati, servizi di backup, integrazione con la piattaforma Moodle, e accesso protetto ad Internet. La versione odierna di “Sugar on a Stick” v1 Strawberry è pensata per la sperimentazione in classe (<link url="mailto:feedback@sugarlabs.org">feedback</link>); la prossima versione sarà rilasciata entro la fine del 2009.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>"Ad un anno dalla fondazione, Sugar Labs sta rilasciando quanto promesso per il suo secondo milione di studenti" commenta Walter Bender, fondatore e direttore esecutivo. "Sugar viene preferito perché offre grandi opportunità educative ai giovani allievi: attraente e di facile approccio. Sugar on a Stick è un modo eccezionalmente semplice per provare Sugar senza dover installare nulla sul proprio computer. Si tratta inoltre di una soluzione ottima per computer vecchi, lenti o per netbook non particolarmente potenti. Esiste una versione specifica per OLPC XO-1 e questa sarà la versione distribuita con i nuovi XO-1.5 laptop a partire dal prossimo autunno."</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar on a Stick fornisce un ambiente coerente e consistente per le attività. Permette una riduzione di costi offrendo adattabilità a molteplici soluzioni hardware, permettendo alle scuole di conservare e riutilizzare gli investimenti in hardware effettuati nel passato. Gli studenti potranno beneficiare della accresciuta possibilità di utilizzare anche a casa i propri strumenti didattici; portando a casa “Sugar on a Stick”, ogni studente ritroverà il proprio ambiente di lavoro scolastico abituale, anche utilizzando computer di famigliari. Permetterà inoltre ad ogni utilizzatore di continuare a utilizzare le proprie applicazioni e contenuti anche off-line, posto che non tutti possano disporre di connessioni ad internet a casa.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Come supporto allo sforzo di rendere “Sugar on a Stick” pronto per l’utilizzo in classe, Sugar Labs ha ricevuto un sussidio di $20,000da parte della Gould Charitable Foundation per rilasciare Sugar presso la  Gardner Pilot Academy, una scuola elementare pubblica situata in una delle aree di Boston, Massachusetts, caratterizzata da una grande varietà culturale e linguistica.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Le Attività di Apprendimento sono il cuore di Sugar. “Sugar on a Stick” include 40 attività  preinstallate per catturare l’interesse dei giovani studenti, fra queste Leggi, Scrivi, Disegna, e l’ambiente Etoys. Altre centinaia di attività sono disponibili per essere liberamente scaricate dalla <link url="http://activities.sugarlabs.org">Sugar Activity Library</link>. La maggior parte delle attività "Sugarized" possiedono funzionalità di collaborazione native; gli studenti ed i docenti possono lavorare, giocare ed imparare tutti insieme condividendo le stesse attività. La “Sugar Learning Platform” è aperta, quindi approfittando del lavoro di altri progetti OpenSource, software didattico per bambini già esistente può essere integrato; per esempio, la famosa suite GCompris comprendente più di 100 attività didattiche e ludiche sviluppata nel corso degli scorsi cinque anni da Bruno Coudoin è stata recentemente integrata, comprendendo fra le altre Attività come Scacchi, Geografia e Sudoku. Docenti e genitori interessati a valutare le attività di Sugar e la sua innovativa interfaccia utente specificamente progettata per i bambini possono visionare i filmati disponibili sul canale recentemente attivato da <link url="http://www.dailymotion.com/sugarlabs">Sugar Labs su Dailymotion</link>.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>I partecipanti a LinuxTag sono caldamente invitati ad incontrare i collaboratori di Sugar Labs presso lo stand 7.2a 110a.</paragraph>
		</language>
		<language id="nederlands">
			<title>Sugar Labs kondigt aan dat Sugar on a Stick nu beschikbaar is; dit leerplatform draait op elke pc of netbook.</title>
			<paragraph>LinuxTag, Berlijn, 24 juni 2009: Sugar Labs™ is de non-profit organisatie die het Sugar Leerplatform levert aan meer dan één miljoen kinderen over de hele wereld. Zij kondigt aan dat nu Sugar on a Stck versie 1 beschikbaar is onder de naam "Strawberry". Het is gratis op te halen bij <link url="www.sugarlabs.org">www.sugarlabs.org</link> en te installeren op een 1 GB flash drive. Daarna kan Sugar direct worden opgestart op een PC of netbook. Het draait ook op recente Macs met een hulp CD en in Windows met gebruik van virtualisatie.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar on a Stick is ontworpen in combinatie met een School Server, waarmee het volgende kan worden verzorgd: Distributie van informatie/leerstof (1) huiswerk verzamelen; (2) backups maken; (3) integratie met Moodle; (4) gefilterde toegang tot het internet. Deze "Strawberry" versie is bedoeld om in de klas te testen; feedback zal in de volgende versie worden opgenomen en komt tegen het einde van 2009 beschikbaar.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>"Eén jaar na oprichting maakt Sugar Labs haar beloften waar voor haar tweede miljoen studenten," zegt Walter Bender, oprichter en direkteur. "Sugar heeft de voorkeur, want het is een superieure leeromgeving voor jonge kinderen: motiverend en betaalbaar. Sugar on a Stick is een geweldige manier om het uit te proberen zonder de harde schijf te veranderen. Het is ook geschikt voor oudere pc’s and langzamer netbooks. Er is een versie voor de OLPC XO-1 en het zal geleverd worden met de nieuwere XO-1.5 laptops in de herfst."</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar on a Stick geeft een samenhangend en consistente werkomgeving. Het vermindert kosten doordat het op veel hardware kan worden geïnstalleerd, zodat scholen hun bestaande apparatuur kunnen blijven gebruiken. Het komt de leerlingen ten goede dat zij hun vertrouwde Sugar on a Stick omgeving mee naar huis kunnen nemen en het ook kunnen delen met hun ouders. Het geeft ook off-line toegang tot hun activiteiten en leerstof, daar niet iedere leerling thuis internet heeft.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Als onderdeel van een voortdurende inspanning om Sugar on a Stick klaar te maken voor de klas, heeft Sugar Labs een donatie van $20000 ontvangen van Gould Charitable Foundation om Sugar te installeren op de Gardner Pilot Academy, een openbare basisschool in een wijk van Boston, Massachusetts met één van de grootste verscheidenheid aan achtergronden qua cultuur en taal.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Leeractiviteiten zijn het hart van Sugar. Sugar on a Stick bevat veertig activiteiten voor jonge leerlingen zoals Lezen, Schrijven, Tekenen en eToys. Er zijn nog honderden andere Activiteiten gratis op te halen bij de Sugar Activiteiten Bibliotheek. De meeste van deze Activiteiten hebben samenwerking ingebouwd: leerlingen en onderwijskrachten werken, spelen en leren samen.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Het Sugar Leerplatform is open, dus andere bestaande open source projecten voor kinderen kunnen er in geïntegreerd worden; zo is de bekende GCompris suite van honderd Activiteiten onlangs toegevoegd aan Sugar, met Activiteiten als Schaken, Aardrijkskunde en Sudoka. Dit project werd de afgelopen vijf jaar door Bruno Coudoin ontwikkeld.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Leerkrachten en ouders die geïnteresseerd zijn in Sugar Activiteiten en de moderne interface voor kinderen kunnen korte videos bekijken bij de onlangs geopende Sugar Labs Dailymotion kanaal. Bezoekers aan LinuxTag zijn welkom bij stand 7.2a 110a om te komen praten met Sugar Labs medewerkers.</paragraph>
		</language>
	</pressrelease>
	<pressrelease sortdate="20090422">
		<date>22 Apr 2009</date>
		<language id="english">
			<attachment url="press/SugarLabsPR_en_20090422.pdf">PDF</attachment>
			<title>Sugar Labs Announces Beta‑1 of Sugar on a Stick, LiveUSB Version of Sugar Learning Platform for Children</title>
			<paragraph>Cambridge, MA, April 22, 2009: Sugar Labs™ announces the availability for testing of Sugar on a Stick Beta‑1. This version of the free open-source Sugar Learning Platform, available at <link url="http://www.sugarlabs.org">www.sugarlabs.org</link> for loading on any 1 Gb or greater USB stick, is designed to facilitate exploration of the award-winning Sugar interface beyond its original platform, the One Laptop per Child XO‑1, to such varied hardware as aging PCs and recent Macs to the latest netbooks.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Teachers and parents interested in trying Sugar with children can download the Sugar on a Stick beta‑1 file from the Sugar Labs website and load it onto a USB stick by following the instructions at <link url="https://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_on_a_Stick">wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_on_a_Stick</link>.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Walter Bender, Executive Director of Sugar Labs, said “Sugar is perfectly suited for children in the classroom with its simple, colorful interface, built-in collaboration, and open architecture. Sugar on a Stick lets you start a computer with Sugar and store a child’s data on the stick without touching the host computer’s hard disk. Sugar’s Activities such as Write, a shared word processor, and the recently announced InfoSlicer Activity, which enables teachers to easily collect and package web-based content for the classroom, benefit fully from Sugar’s collaboration features.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Caroline Meeks of Solution Grove (<link url="http://www.solutiongrove.com">www.solutiongrove.com</link>), the Sugar on a Stick project manager, commented: “We’re counting on teachers to help us improve Sugar on a Stick as we work towards our Version‑1 release scheduled for Q3 2009. We just presented Sugar on a Stick at the FOSS VT conference (<link url="http://www.ncose.org/node/47">http://www.ncose.org/node/47</link>) where it generated great interest, and our real-world tests at local sites with varied aging PCs have been very encouraging.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar testers are invited to send bug information and constructive criticism to <link url="mailto:feedback@sugarlabs.org">feedback@sugarlabs.org</link>. “We won’t be able to reply to every message,” continued Ms. Meeks, “but we will read every one in order to make Sugar on a Stick a reliable learning tool in budget-stretched classrooms by the fall.”</paragraph>
		</language>
		<language id="français">
			<attachment url="press/SugarLabsPR_fr_20090422.pdf">PDF</attachment>
			<title>Sugar Labs annonce la bêta-1 de Sugar on a Stick, version LiveUSB de Sugar, la plate-forme d’apprentissage pour enfants</title>
			<paragraph>Cambridge, MA, April 22, 2009: Sugar Labs™ annonce la disponibilité pour tests de la version Bêta-1 de Sugar on a Stick. Cette version du logiciel libre Sugar Learning Platform, disponible sur www.sugarlabs.org pour téléchargement dans n’importe quelle clef USB de 1 Go ou plus, a été conçue pour permettre d’explorer la célèbre interface Sugar au-delà de sa plate-forme d’origine, le XO-1 de One Laptop per Child, sur toutes sortes d’ordinateurs, des PCs anciens aux Macintosh récents en passant par les nouveaux netbooks.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Les enseignants et parents qui veulent essayer Sugar avec des enfants peuvent télécharger le fichier bêta-1 de Sugar on a Stick sur le site web de Sugar Labs et le charger sur une clef USB en suivant les instructions sur <link url="https://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_on_a_Stick">wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/Sugar_on_a_Stick</link>.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Walter Bender, le directeur exécutif de Sugar Labs, a dit “Sugar est parfaitement adapté aux élèves avec son interface simple et vivante, pensée pour le travail en commun, et avec son architecture ouverte. Sugar on a Stick vous permet de démarrer un ordinateur avec Sugar et de stocker les données de l’enfant dans la clef sans toucher au disque dur de l’ordinateur hôte. Les Activités de Sugar telles que Write, un traitement de texte partagé, et l’Activité InfoSlicer annoncé récemment, qui permet aux enseignants de collectionner et réunir facilement des contenus du web pour la classe, bénéficient pleinement des caractéristiques collaboratives de Sugar.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Caroline Meeks de Solution Grove (<link url="http://www.solutiongrove.com">www.solutiongrove.com</link>), gestionnaire du projet Sugar on a Stick, a commenté : “Nous comptons sur les enseignants pour nous aider à améliorer Sugar on a Stick tandis que nous continuons à travailler sur la Version-1 prévue pour le troisième trimestre 2009. Nous venons de présenter Sugar on a Stick à la conference FOSS VT (<link url="http://www.ncose.org/node/47">http://www.ncose.org/node/47</link>) où il a suscité beaucoup d’intérêt, et nos tests sur le terrain avec des PCs variés et anciens ont été tres encourageants.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Les testeurs de Sugar sont invités à envoyer des informations sur tout bogue et autres critiques constructives à l’adresse suivante: <link url="mailto:feedback@sugarlabs.org">feedback@sugarlabs.org</link>. “Nous ne pourrons pas répondre à chaque message,” a continué Mme Meeks, “mais nous allons lire chacun afin de rendre Sugar on a Stick un outil fiable dans les classes qui manquent de ressources d’ici la rentrée.”</paragraph>
		</language>
	</pressrelease>
	<pressrelease sortdate="20090316">
		<date>16 Mar 2009</date>
		<language id="english">
			<attachment url="press/SugarLabsPR_en_20090316.pdf">PDF</attachment>
			<title>Sugar Labs Nonprofit Announces New Version of Sugar Learning Platform for Children, Runs on Netbooks and PCs</title>
			<paragraph>Cambridge, MA, March 16, 2009: Sugar Labs™ announces the availability of version 0.84 of the Sugar Learning Platform for the One Laptop Per Child XO-1, classroom PCs, and netbook computers. Designed from the ground up for children, the Sugar computer environment is used by almost one-million students aged 5 to 12 in over 40 countries every school day. This improved version features new collaborative Sugar Activities and, in response to teacher feedback, the ability to easily suspend and resume Activities, saving time in the classroom.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Walter Bender, Executive Director of Sugar Labs, commented: “We’re excited about this release, which runs on more PCs than before and has great new Activities for kids to explore together such as a Mindmap Activity, a critical-thinking tool used to create diagrams representing words and ideas around a central keyword, and a Portfolio Activity, an assessment tool that makes it even simpler for teachers and parents to review a child’s progress. The Sugar Journal, which provides automatic backup and history of students’ work, has new features to make it easier for students to annotate their work and to revisit and revise past projects. The new Infoslicer Activity enables teachers to quickly and easily select web-based content to edit, package, and distribute as teaching materials. And for older students curious about how computers work, the View Source function is now universal to all Activities.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>The Sugar Learning Platform is free open-source software; it is available for download at www.sugarlabs.org. The native interface of the One Laptop Per Child project’s XO-1 in daily use around the globe, Sugar has been translated into 26 languages with 50 more languages underway. 24/7 community support is available online. Sugar is available on major GNU/Linux distributions, recent Apple Macintosh™ computers with virtualization, and Windows™ PCs via a GNU/Linux liveCD, which doesn’t touch the hard disk. Sugar on a Stick, a liveUSB version designed to simplify classroom use of Sugar, is scheduled for release in Q3 2009.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>The Sugar Learning Platform is part of the permanent collection of the Museum of Modern Art in New York and was awarded a silver medal in the International Design Excellence Awards ’08. Its innovative “learning-centric” approach has earned praise from educators worldwide. Sugar Activities, unique to the platform, allow students to study and create together; students learn both from the teacher and from each other.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Mr. Bender commented, “Sugar 0.84 is an important step as we work toward version 1.0 of Sugar on a Stick, which will greatly simplify evaluation and use of Sugar in the classroom. Sugar on a Stick will start Sugar from a simple USB memory stick on nearly any recent computer from netbooks to desktops, and most older PCs as well, without interfering with pre-existing software installations.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>“As we approach the one-millionth child ‘learning to learn’ with Sugar on the OLPC XO-1, we call for volunteers to join us—a challenge to educate for developers, designers, translators, and deployers,” Mr. Bender said. “In particular, we need testers to help us make Sugar on a Stick a robust solution available anywhere there is a computer.”</paragraph>
		</language>
		<language id="español">
			<attachment url="press/SugarLabsPR_es_20090316.pdf">PDF</attachment>
			<title>La Asociación sin fines de lucro Sugar Labs Anuncia su Nueva Versión de la Plataforma de Aprendizaje Sugar para Niños que Funciona en Notebooks y PCs</title>
			<paragraph>Cambridge, MA, March 16, 2009: Sugar Labs™ anuncia que la versión 0.84 de la Plataforma de Aprendizaje de Sugar para la XO-1 de OLPC, las PCs de aula y los notebooks  ya se encuentra disponible. Diseñada desde un principio para los niños, el entorno Sugar es usado aproximadamente por un millón de estudiantes, cuyas edades fluctúan entre los 5 y 12 años, en aproximadamente 40 países durante todos los días del calendario  escolar. Esta versión mejorada se caracteriza por poseer nuevas Actividades colaborativas. Asimismo, y en respuesta a la retroalimentación brindada por los docentes, posee la capacidad para detener y reanudar las Actividades con facilidad, lo cual permite ahorrar tiempo en el aula.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Walter Bender, Director Ejecutivo de Sugar Labs, comentó lo siguiente: “Nos encontramos muy emocionados con este lanzamiento que funciona en un mayor número de PCs que antes y posee Actividades nuevas y únicas para que los niños investiguen juntos, tales como la Actividad Mapa Mental, una herramienta de pensamiento crítico que se usa para crear diagramas que representan conceptos e ideas que se encuentran relacionados y dispuestos alrededor de una palabra clave o de una idea central y la Actividad Portafolio, una herramienta de evaluación que brinda mayor facilitad para que tanto los docentes como los padres de familia revisen el progreso que realiza el niño.” Igualmente, el Diario Sugar, que proporciona un back up automático y el historial del trabajo de los estudiantes, posee nuevas características a fin de permitirles tomar apuntes o hacer comentarios respecto a su trabajo, así como volver a visitar y revisar proyectos anteriores. Por su parte, la nueva Actividad Infoslicer (Selecciona y Corta Información) permite a los docentes seleccionar el contenido de páginas Web con facilidad y rapidez para editarlo, organizarlo y distribuirlo como material pedagógico. De igual modo, para los estudiantes mayores que tienen curiosidad por saber cómo funcionan las computadoras, la función Vista de Código es actualmente general para todas las Actividades”.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>La Plataforma de Aprendizaje Sugar es un software libre y de código abierto  y se encuentra disponible para ser descargado en www.sugarlabs.org. Sugar, la interfaz originaria de la XO-1 de OLPC de uso diario en todo el mundo, ha sido traducida a 26 idiomas y tiene 50 idiomas más en proceso de traducción. El apoyo comunitario se encuentra disponible en línea las 24 horas al día/7 días a la semana. Sugar se encuentra disponible en las principales distribuciones GNU/Linux, las últimas computadoras con virtualización Apple Macintosh™ y las PCs Windows™  ejecutadas vía un Live CD de GNU/Linux que no modifica el disco duro. Igualmente, en el tercer trimestre del 2009, se ha programado el lanzamiento de Sugar en formato de tarjeta de memoria (memoria flash) extraíble, una versión de Live USB diseñada para simplificar el uso de Sugar en el aula.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>La plataforma de aprendizaje de Sugar forma parte de la colección permanente del Museo de Arte Moderno de Nueva York. Asimismo, en los International Design Excellence Awards ’08 (Premios Internacionales a la Excelencia en Diseño 2008) le fue otorgada una medalla de plata. Su innovador enfoque “centrado en el aprendizaje” ha recibido elogios por parte de los docentes a nivel mundial. Las Actividades de Sugar, exclusivas de la plataforma, permiten a los alumnos estudiar y crear juntos. Los estudiantes aprenden tanto del docente como de otros alumnos.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>El Sr. Bender comentó lo siguiente: “Sugar 0.84 representa un paso importante a medida que se trabaja para lograr la versión 1.0 de Sugar en formato de tarjeta de memoria extraíble que simplificará, en gran medida, la evaluación y el uso de Sugar en el aula. Asimismo, este formato de tarjeta de memoria extraíble hace posible que Sugar se ejecute a partir de un simple formato de memoria USB en casi cualquier computadora actual desde las notebooks (computadora portátil) hasta las desktops (computadora personal), así como en la mayoría de PCs más antiguas, sin interferir con las instalaciones de software preexistente”.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>“A medida que nos aproximamos al millón de niños “aprendiendo a aprender” con Sugar en la XO-1 de OLPC, solicitamos voluntarios que se unan a nosotros- un reto para los programadores, diseñadores, traductores e implementadores”, refirió el Sr. Bender. “Necesitamos especialmente probadores de software que nos ayuden a hacer de Sugar en formato de tarjeta de memoria extraíble una sólida solución que se encuentre disponible dondequiera que exista una computadora.”</paragraph>
		</language>
		<language id="français">
			<attachment url="press/SugarLabsPR_fr_20090316.pdf">PDF</attachment>
			<title>Sugar Labs, organisation à but non lucratif, annonce la sortie de la nouvelle version de la plateforme d’apprentissage pour enfants Sugar pour PC et netbooks</title>
			<paragraph>Cambridge, MA, le 16 mars 2009: Sugar Labs™ annonce la sortie de la version 0.84 de sa plateforme d’apprentissage Sugar destinée au XO-1 du projet One Laptop Per Child, aux micro-ordinateurs des établissements scolaires, et aux ordinateurs netbook. Conçu pour enfants de A à Z, l’environnement Sugar est utilisé par près d’un million d’élèves de 5 à 12 ans dans plus de 40 pays, tous les jours.  Cette nouvelle version contient de nouvelles Activités Sugar à faire à plusieurs en travail collaboratif et, à la demande des professeurs, prévoit la possibilité d’interrompre et de reprendre facilement les Activités, pour gagner du temps en classe.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Walter Bender, Directeur Exécutif de Sugar Labs, a dit: "Cette nouvelle version est compatible avec beaucoup plus de PC qu’auparavant, et contient de nouvelles Activités que les enfants adoreront découvrir ensemble, comme l’Activité Mindmap, un outil qui développe l’esprit critique et permet de créér des diagrammes représentant des mots et des idées à partir d’un mot-clé central, et l’Activité Portfolio, un outil d’évaluation permettant aux professeurs et aux parents d’établir très simplement les progrès réalisés par l’enfant. Le Journal Sugar, qui fournit une sauvegarde automatique et un historique du travail de l’élève, comporte de nouvelles fonctionnalités permettant aux élèves d’annoter plus facilement leurs travaux, et de reprendre ou réviser des projets déjà réalisés. La nouvelle activité Infoslicer permet aux professeurs de sélectionner rapidement et facilement du contenu pris sur internet, de le modifier et de le remettre en forme pour le redistribuer comme documents pédagogiques. Et pour les élèves plus grands qui veulent savoir comment marchent les ordinateurs, la fonction View Source (voir code source) a été généralisée à toutes les Activités.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>La plateforme d’apprentissage Sugar est un logiciel libre. Elle peut être téléchargée sur le site www.sugarlabs.org. Interface d’origine du projet One Laptop Per Child déjà utilisé quotidiennement dans le monde entier, Sugar a déjà été traduite dans 26 langues et 50 autres doivent suivre. Un soutien technique de la communauté est disponible en ligne 24h/24, 7 jours/7. Sugar est disponible sur toutes les grandes distributions GNU/Linux, les ordinateurs Apple MacintoshTM récents avec virtualisation, et pour PC sous WindowsTM via un liveCD GNU/Linux, qui ne touche pas au disque dur. Sugar on a Stick, une version liveUSB censée simplifier l’utilisation de Sugar en classe, doit sortir au 3e trimestre 2009.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>La plateforme d’apprentissage Sugar fait partie de la collection permanente du Musée d’Art Moderne de New York, et a reçu la médaille d’argent au Palmarès 2008 de l’excellence du design international (International Design Excellence Awards). Son approche innovante, centrée sur l’apprentissage, a été saluée par les enseignants du monde entier.  Les Activités Sugar, disponibles exclusivement sur cette plateforme, permettent aux élèves d’éudier et de créér ensemble: les étudiants apprennent du professeur mais aussi les uns des autres.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Selon M. Bender, “Sugar 0.84 est une étape importante vers la version 1.0 de Sugar on a Stick, qui va considérablement simplifier l’évaluation et l’utilisation de Sugar en classe. Avec Sugar on a Stick, on pourra lancer Sugar à partir d’une simple clé USB sur la plupart des ordinateurs récents, des netbooks aux ordinateurs de bureau, et aussi sur la plupart des vieux PC, sans perturber les logiciels déjà installés.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>“Alors que nous nous approchons du millionième enfant “apprenant à apprendre” avec Sugar sur le XO-1 de One Laptop per Child, nous appelons de nouveau bénévoles à venir nous aider à relever ce défi éducatif: développeurs, concepteurs, traducteurs, et déployeurs”, a déclaré M. Bender. “Nous avons notamment besoin de testeurs pour nous aider à faire de Sugar on a Stick une solution robuste qui fonctionnera avec n’importe quel ordinateur.”</paragraph>
		</language>
		<language id="deutsch">
			<attachment url="press/SugarLabsPR_de_20090316.pdf">PDF</attachment>
			<title>Sugar Labs kündigt neue Version von Sugar an—die Lernplattform für Kinder läuft auf Netbooks und PCs</title>
			<paragraph>Cambridge, MA, 16. März, 2009: Sugar Labs™ hat die Version 0.84 der Lernplattform Sugar freigegeben. Die Software ist auf dem XO-1 von One Laptop Per Child, PCs und Netbooks einsetzbar. Die speziell für Kinder entwickelte Plattform wird von fast einer Million Schülern im Alter von 5 bis 12 Jahren in über 40 Ländern täglich im Schulunterricht eingesetzt.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Walter Bender, Geschäftsführer von Sugar Labs, sagt hierzu: “Wir sind gespannt auf die neue Version, die auf mehr PCs läuft als zuvor und neue,  interessante Activities zum gemeinsamen Erkunden beinhaltet. Zum Beispiel die Mindmap Activity, ein Werkzeug zum Erstellen von Diagrammen, die Beziehungen zwischen einem Schlüsselwort und diesem zugeordneten Begriffen aufzeigen. Oder die Portfolio Activity, ein Bewertungswerkzeug, das es Lehrern und Eltern einfacher macht, den Fortschritt eines Kindes zu beurteilen. Das Journal, eine Art Tagebuch, das dem Schüler die chronologische Aufzeichnung seiner Aktivitäten bereitstellt, wurde erweitert. Der Schüler hat es nun leichter seine Arbeiten zu kommentieren und seine Projekte zu überarbeiten. Die neue Infoslicer Activity ermöglicht es Lehrern, schnell und einfach web-basierte Inhalte zu editieren, zusammenzustellen und als Lehrmaterial bereitzustellen. Schüler, die an der Funktionsweise eines Computers interessiert sind, können die View Source Funktion nutzen um tiefere Einblicke zu erhalten. Außerdem wurde in der Entwicklung der Software auf Verbesserungsvorschläge von Lehrern eingegangen. So ist es nun einfacher, vorangegangene Activities fortzuführen, wodurch im Unterricht Zeit eingespart werden kann.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Die Lernplattform Sugar ist Open Source Software und kann von www.sugarlabs.org heruntergeladen werden. Sugar wurde in 26 Sprachen übersetzt und 50 weitere Übersetzungen sind in Bearbeitung. Die Sugar-Gemeinschaft ist Online immer für Fragen und Anregungen offen. Die Plattform ist erhältlich in allen größeren Linux-Distributionen. Sugar kann als Live-System unter Windows™ von einem CD-Image gestartet werden und kann auf Apple Macintosh™  Computern virtualisiert ausgeführt werden. Sugar on a Stick, ein Live-System, das von USB-Speichermedien gestartet wird, und den Einsatz in Computerlaboren erleichtern soll, wird voraussichtlich im dritten Quartal von 2009 erscheinen.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Die Lernplattform Sugar ist Teil der ständigen Ausstellung des Museum of Modern Art in New York. 2008 erhielt sie die Silber-Medaille des International Design Excellence Awards in der Kategorie Interactive Product Experiences. Ihr innovativer lernorientierter Ansatz erhielt weltweites Lob von Pädagogen. Sugar Activities, die einmalig für diese Plattform sind, ermöglichen es den Schülern gemeinsam zu lernen und kreativ zu werden, Schüler können sowohl von ihrem Lehrer als auch voneinander lernen.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Bender fügt hinzu: “Sugar 0.84 ist ein wichtiger Schritt im Hinblick auf die Version 1.0 von Sugar on a Stick, die die Evaluation und die Anwendung von Sugar im Unterricht vereinfachen wird. Sugar on a Stick lädt Sugar von einem USB-Speichermedium auf nahezu jedem gängigen Computer, ob Netbook oder Desktop PC, ohne dabei mit der bereits installierten Software in Konflikt zu geraten.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>“Weil bald das millionste Kind mit Sugar auf dem OLPC XO-1 ‘lernt zu lernen’ laden wir alle Freiwilligen dazu ein, mitzumachen—eine Herausforderung für Entwickler, Pädagogen, Designer, Übersetzer und Anwender,” sagt Bender. “Vor allem brauchen wir Software-Tester, die uns helfen aus Sugar on a Stick eine Alternative zu vorhandener Software auf allen verfügbaren Computern zu machen.”</paragraph>
		</language>
	</pressrelease>
	<pressrelease sortdate="20081209">
		<date>9 Dec 2008</date>
		<language id="english">
			<title>Sugar Labs joins the Software Freedom Conservancy</title>
			<paragraph>Boston, MA, December 9, 2008: Sugar Labs today announced its membership in the Software Freedom Conservancy, an organization of free and open source software projects. Sugar Labs supports the free and open source desktop environment, Sugar, originally created for the One Laptop per Child Project (OLPC). The Sugar community now has an active global developer base that is focused on engaging young children in learning through computing and the Internet. As a member of the Conservancy the Sugar community will work to accelerate the adoption of the Sugar learning platform and strengthening the project by attracting new industry members and community contributors.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>In May 2008, the Sugar project became independent of OLPC, making Sugar available to a wider community of Sugar developers and users. Subsequently Sugar has been ported to Debian, Ubuntu, and other GNU/Linux distributions. Sugar can now run on almost any computer hardware. In October 2008, Sugar Labs released Sugar Version 0.82, which features enhanced usability and stability. In November, Sugar announced the availability of the pre-alpha version of “Sugar on a Stick”, a LiveUSB image of Sugar that gives children access to Sugar on any computer with just a USB key. Joining the Conservancy is an important milestone in the path towards making Sugar available to children everywhere.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Founded in March 2006, the Conservancy allows developers of its member projects to unite under a common organization which provides much-needed administrative services to them. This structure spares each software project the burden of starting and maintaining its own independent non-profit organization. Sugar Labs has joined as the Conservancy’s fifteenth member project.</paragraph>
		</language>
	</pressrelease>
	<pressrelease sortdate="20080515">
		<date>15 May 2008</date>
		<language id="english">
			<title>New foundation focused on taking the Sugar user interface to the next level of usability and utility</title>
			<paragraph>Cambridge, Mass., May 15, 2008. Sugar Labs Foundation is being established to further extend Sugar, the highly acclaimed open source “learn learning” software platform that was originally developed for the One Laptop per Child (OLPC) XO laptop. Sugar is the core of the XO laptop’s human-computer interface; it provides a fun, easy-to-use, social experience that promotes sharing and learning. Sugar Labs will focus on providing a software ecosystem that enhances learning on the XO laptop as well as other laptops distributed by other companies, such as the ASUS Eee PC. Consistent with the OLPC mission to provide opportunities for learning, an independent Sugar Labs Foundation can deliver learning software to other hardware vendors and, consequently, reach more children.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Sugar Labs will take a proven learning concept to the next level of refinement, stability, and cohesiveness, and will be a unifying catalyst for free and open-source learning systems across multiple distribution and hardware platforms. The Labs will provide support to a community of developers focused on learning as well as support for the learners. The Sugar platform has already been bundled with the most recent release of the Ubuntu and Fedora GNU/Linux distributions.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Walter Bender, former president of software and content at OLPC, is helping to launch Sugar Labs, working closely with the developers and community members from around the world who have played the lead roles in the development of the Sugar user interface (UI). Prior to OLPC, Bender was executive director and a founding member of the Media Lab at MIT. He has participated in much of the pioneering research in the field of electronic publishing and personalized, interactive multimedia.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>In order to provide a rich learning experience to as many of the world’s children as possible, it is critical to not just provide computers to children, but to ensure that the software that runs on the computers maximizes the potential for engaging in activities that promote learning: exploration, expression, and collaboration. By being independent of any specific hardware platform and by remaining dedicated to the principles of free and open-source software, Sugar Labs ensures that others can develop diverse interfaces and applications from which governments and schools can choose. An independent Sugar Labs ensures that the community can continue the development of a highly innovative interface that is already engaging children in learning in more than two-dozen countries worldwide.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>“This is a very exciting time in the development of software for children’s education,” said Walter Bender. “In the first generation of the Sugar UI, the free and open-source community has demonstrated an exceptional ability to create a platform that enables children to explore the world, share their discoveries and express themselves. As a separate foundation, we will be able to advance Sugar’s development even further and make it available on multiple distributions and hardware platforms.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Many of the core Sugar developers are participating in the launch, including Marco Pesenti Gritti, Bert Freudenberg, Simon Schampijer, Bernardo Innocenti, Aaron Kaplan, Christoph Derndorfer, and Tomeu Vizoso.</paragraph>
			<paragraph>Bert Freudenberg, one of the developers of the Etoys activity, commented, “Expanding Sugar to more hardware platforms gives a great boost to all developers of educational software. Sugar is the first system specifically aimed at helping children to learn while supporting a rich variety of contributed applications. As third-party developers, my colleagues at Viewpoints Research Institute look forward to a great relationship with Sugar Labs.”</paragraph>
			<paragraph>“Sugar has been brought to maturity by OLPC and a relatively small team of community supporters,” said Tomeu Vizoso. “The time has come to unlock Sugar’s potential as a global education project; the creation of the Sugar Labs is the next step expanding upon a project where people from all around the world can contribute to improving education, with the assurance that their efforts will be of benefit to everyone.”</paragraph>
		</language>
	</pressrelease>
</page>
